(Nippon TV 60th Anniversary Television Special)
（日本電視台開台60年特別電影）
(Yomiuri TV 55th Anniversary)
（讀賣電視台開台55年）
(TMS Entertainment 50th Anniversary Commemorative Movie)
(TMS動畫製作50週年紀念電影）
("Lupin the Third" 45th anniversary Television Special)
『魯邦三世』連載45週年特別電影）
("Detective Conan" 20th Anniversary Television Special)
『名偵探柯南』連載20週年特別電影）
Team 4, in position.
4號，固定完畢
Roger that.
了解
This is team 2, in position.
這裡是2號，固定完畢
Team 2, roger that.
2號，了解
Team 3, in position.
3號車，固定OK
Team 1, in position.
1號車，完畢
Roger that.
了解
Inspector, all vehicles are in position!
警部，所有車輛皆已就位
Strike Team, what's the situation inside?
攻堅小組，回報內部情況
Just like what you've expected,
正如警部所說的
the security system has been destroyed.
保全系統全數遭到破壞
Where's the diamond?
鑽石呢？
It's gone. The protective case is broken.
不見了，防護罩遭到突破
This is the B team.
這裡是B小隊
Target is not found on the first floor of the emergency staircase.
一樓逃生梯並未發現目標
We are getting ready to head up.
準備向上搜索
No need to lower down your voice.
不必刻意降低音量
Do your best to force the target to move upwards.
想辦法把目標往上面逼
Roger that.
了解
Okay. Let's go through our operation plan again.
好，再次確認行動內容
No matter where he flies off from,
不管那小子打算從哪裡起飛
our four jet streams
四道噴射氣流
will blow him into the Tsukishima River.
都會狠狠把他吹到月島川
Then, we'll scoop him up like
再來就像是在玩撈金魚一樣
the Goldfish Scooping Game.
把他撈起來
Today, he won't get away from me.
今天絕對要他插翅也難飛
Will it be so easy to blow him into the water?
他會乖乖被吹進河裡嗎？
He might counterattack us with his Card Gun.
也有可能會用撲克槍進行反擊
Although his ammunition is tough, they are still poker cards.
他的子彈雖硬，終究是撲克牌造型
They'll be affected by the jet streams.
很難不受到風的影響
He likes to spread out his cape, use it as a hang-glider
讓披風飄揚，整個人掛在風箏上
and shoot out poker cards.
再發射撲克牌
Because he likes to act cool,
因為愛裝模作樣
wind will become Kiddo's weakness.
使得基德容易被風影響
Kiddo!
基德…
Inspector!
警部！
Here you are, Kiddo.
你出現了啊，基德
Get into position!
全員就定位
Yes, Inspector!
是
I have the diamond now.
鑽石確實已在我手上
Who is that person?
那傢伙是誰啊
Operation Kiddo Arrest commences now!
捕捉基德行動開始！
Start your turbines right now.
所有車輛啟動渦輪機
Kiddo is heading towards the left.
基德朝東邊移動
Team 2 and team 4, execute plan B.
2號、4號，執行B模式
We got him.
逮到人了
Serve you right, Kiddo.
臭基德
You were so frightened that you forgot to show your hang-glider?
嚇到連風箏都亮不出來啦
He's 50 meters away from Tsukishima River.
距離月島川還有50公尺
Arrest Team at Tsukishima River, raise the net!
月島川捕捉隊，開始收網
Kiddo has fired a gun!
基德持手槍射擊！持手槍射擊！
Kiddo fired a gun?
基德竟然…會用槍？
Kiddo has escaped with a Yakata Boat.
基德利用屋形船脫逃
He's moving upstream along Tsukishima River!
朝月島川上游移動
Where's the helicopter?
直升機上哪裡去了？
We didn't prepare any helicopters for this operation.
這次行動計劃並沒有安排直升機
-Kiddo fired a gun? -We have coastguards on the boats.
- 基德持手槍射擊… - 那裡還有水上警察的船隻
This is such a hindrance!
真礙事！
This huge net is in the way!
弄這麼大張網找人麻煩啊！
We can't chase after him!
無法追蹤！
Kiddo, stop right there!
基德，別跑！
I won't let you get away!
休想逃走！
Looks like he won't be defeated so easily.
這點手段是弄不倒他的啊…
(Original work of Monkey Punch x Gosho Aoyama)
（原作） (Monkey Punch青山剛昌）
Zantetsuken.
斬鐵劍…
I see.
原來如此
You should've said that from the very start.
幹嘛不一開始就把話講開啊…
Lupin III.
魯邦三世
(Lupin the 3rd VS Detective Conan The Movie)
（魯邦三世 VS 名偵探柯南THE MOVIE)
This man is Lupin III.
這傢伙名叫魯邦三世
His footsteps can be found all over the world.
足跡踏遍全世界
He never gives up a target.
看中的獵物絕不放過
He's the elusive master thief.
是個神出鬼沒的大盜
His partner is Daisuke Jigen.
搭檔名叫次元大介
A professional shooter who can pull out his gun and shoot in 0.3 seconds.
0.3秒就能迅速掏槍射擊的行家
He's a loyal and calm
是個很講義氣的冷靜神槍手
(Don't call me Papa!) -sharpshooter.
（不准喊我爸爸！)
Goemon Ishikawa XIII.
第十三代石川五右衛門
An expert who has mastered Iaido
精通居合斬的高手
and can cut everything into half.
任何東西都能劈成兩半
He can be a dangerous man when provoked.
一旦被惹毛就會讓風雲變色的男人
Last but not least,
最後還有一位
the mysterious lady, Fujiko Mine.
神祕大姊姊，峰不二子
Even Lupin is not sure
就連魯邦都不清楚
whether she's a female thief or a lady spy.
她到底是女賊還是女間謀
He's always in trouble because of her.
明明老是因為她吃了大苦頭
So, why does he let her tag along?
為什麼還要讓她加入…
That is because cute ladies are Lupin's weakness.
因為魯邦對可愛女生沒轍
So it seems.
聽說是這樣
This boy is a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
這小子是高中生偵探，工藤新一
While on a date with his childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mouri, at an amusement park,
聽說某天和青梅竹馬兼同學的 毛利蘭到遊樂園去玩時
he witnessed a suspicious transaction between some scary-looking men in black.
目擊了可怕黑衣人的可疑交易現場
He was so focused on the transaction
結果他只顧著偷看交易
that he failed to notice one of their partners sneaking up on him from behind.
卻忽略了從背後而來的另一個同夥
He was forced to swallow poison by that man.
他被那名男子強灌了毒藥
When he woke up,
等他醒來時…
it was so shocking,
這真是太驚人了
his body had shrunk.
他的身體竟然已經縮小了
So,
所以
if they found out that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
要是被他們發現工藤新一還活著
not only his life would be in danger,
不但他的性命難保
the people around him would be at risk too.
還會危害到他周遭的親人
Thus, Shinichi Kudo decided to hide his identity
因此決定要隱瞞身分的工藤新一
and named himself Conan Edogawa.
自稱江戶川柯南
He moved in with his girlfriend, Ran, and her father
住進父親以偵探為業的女朋友
who is a detective.
小蘭家中
Forget it then. I'll ask Kiddo for help.
那就算了，人家會去拜託基德大人
Kiddo?
基、基德大人？
Kaito Kiddo. Have you not heard of him before?
怪盜基德啊，你沒聽過嗎？
He's no one.
他算什麼
Although he's known as the Moonlight Magician,
那傢伙雖然被稱為月光下的魔術師
he's still a young high schooler.
不過就是個還在唸高中的毛頭小子
My cup of tea.
哎呀，正合我意
Where is he? Which high school is he in?
你快說是哪裡？是哪所高中？
Tell me, Lupin.
告訴人家嘛，魯邦
I've fulfilled your request
我已經如妳所願
by committing the crime in Kiddo's name.
用基德大人的名義犯案成功了
Good evening, Lupin.
晚安，魯邦
You had made such a showy appearance.
看來你的出場相當引人矚目啊
Since you had seen it, let's cut to the chase.
既然你有在狀況內，就廢話不多說
Deactivate the bomb now.
現在馬上解除引爆密碼
About that,
這點我…
I can't do it.
辦不到
What do you mean?
你說什麼？
Will you really follow my order for that woman?
你真的會為了那個女人 乖乖照我說的吩咐去做嗎…
I'm not sure if I can trust you or not.
我並不確定你是否值得信任
So, it was a test.
是測試啊…
I'm sorry.
抱歉了
A man recommended you to me.
有個男人向我推薦你
According to him, you are the only one
他說能夠偷到櫻桃藍寶石的
who can steal the Cherry Sapphire.
唯有魯邦三世，非你莫屬
Thank you for the compliment.
多謝誇獎
Did I pass the test?
那測試算是及格了嗎？
Of course.
當然
Contact me again after you've gotten the Cherry Sapphire.
拿到櫻桃藍寶石後再和我聯絡
Only then will I deactivate the bomb on her.
到時我就會解除她身上的炸彈
Another thing.
對了
It'll be a waste of time for you to trace this number.
調查這隻號碼只是在浪費時間
Looks like it.
似乎是
Let me ask. Where does the signal come from right now?
順便問一下，目前是從哪裡發話？
It came from the deep mountains of China just now.
剛才還在中國的深山裡
Now, it's coming from the satellite above America.
現在則是來自美國上空的衛星
I don't want to play anymore.
不玩了、不玩了
I'll admit this.
我就老實承認
You are an opponent I should take seriously.
你是個要拿出真本事應付的對手
I'll never forget
我也絕對不會忘記
that my opponent is Lupin III, too.
對手可是魯邦三世
It was perfectly cut in half.
被俐落地一分為二啊
What kind of a weapon could do that?
用什麼武器可以辦到？
Even the bulletproof carbon fiber inside was...
連內層的防彈碳纖維都…
How terrifying.
令人畏懼
Looks like this one
看來還是這個適合你用
-suits you better. -Why did he put so much effort
又何必要大費周章地偷到手
and then, throwing it into someone's bucket?
再丟進別人的水桶裡呢？
I don't get it.
真是讓人搞不懂
In the end, he just wanted to create a scene?
結果就只要引人注意而已吧？
They even laid down such a huge net
這麼一來那麼大規模撒網
and came back
卻只捕到三尾小魚…
-Conan is staring at the TV. -with three little fish.
柯南一直盯著電視看
He looks so dispirited.
無精打采的
I'm always saying this.
我每次都在講啊
He shouldn't act on his own.
誰叫他要自己單獨行動
He lost to the man named Goemon, right?
是敗給那個叫五右衛門的人吧
It's all over the internet.
網路上到處都是
It's said that Lupin III is in Japan now.
魯邦三世人在日本的消息
Goemon is Lupin's accomplice, right?
五右衛門跟魯邦是一夥的對吧？
So, they are in the same area as we are?
所以他們人就在我們這一區？
It's time for your long-awaited quiz.
我來出一道大家期待已久的猜謎吧
Will it be a foolish quiz again?
又是冷笑話猜謎啊？
I'm not in the mood.
現在沒那個心情
No one is looking forward to it.
沒人在期待啦
All of you should do something about that.
你們幾個…做點什麼啊
It doesn't feel right without it.
少了這個就提不起勁說
I really look forward to it.
我超期待的
Will I be able to guess it?
人家猜得出來嗎？
-The change is too obvious. -I love quiz!
- 太明顯了啦，前後態度差這麼多 - 我最喜歡猜謎
I love bad jokes.
我最愛冷笑話了
I even prepared a whiteboard today.
我今天還特地準備了白板呢
I've been waiting for it!
等很久了
You are the best, Professor!
博士太棒了
Look over here!
往我這邊看
I'm looking at you.
我在看了喔
-Among these four types of beans, (1. Soybean 2. Red Bean 3. Broad Bean 4. Snow Pea)
這四種豆類裡頭 (1. 黃豆 2. 紅豆 3. 蠶豆 4. 青豆仁)
-which one is Lupin's favorite?
有一種是魯邦的最愛
-Can you guess? (1. Soybean 2. Red Bean 3. Broad Bean 4. Snow Pea)
猜得出來嗎？ (1. 黃豆 2. 紅豆 3. 蠶豆 4. 青豆仁)
I'll give you five minutes to think.
給你們5分鐘想答案
(Five Minutes Later)
(5分鐘後）
Do you have the answer?
猜到了嗎？
That was fast.
好快
They are all the same after you eat them.
吃下肚子不全都一樣？
Genta.
元太…
We need to consider the properties of the beans, right?
要往豆子的特性上頭想對吧？
The answer is broad bean.
答案是「3. 蠶豆」
Why's that?
怎麼說？
Besides broad bean, the other beans are all alkaline.
除了蠶豆之外，全都是鹼性食品
Only broad bean is acidic, right?
只有蠶豆是酸性食品對吧？
Acidic?
酸性食品？
So?
所以呢？
I got it.
啊...
Lupin
魯邦
-III!   -III! (III and acidic have similar pronunciation in Japanese.)
三世 (日語音同「酸性」)
-Hooray!
萬歲！萬歲！萬歲！
Is this a provocation?
這是在挑釁嗎
This morning, the famous Italian idol,
今天早上，義大利當紅偶像
Emilio Baretti, has arrived in Japan.
艾米利歐·巴瑞帝飛抵日本
His footsteps can be found all over the world.
他的足跡遍布全世界
I thought I wouldn't see him again.
我還以為不會再見面了…
Amazing!
好棒喔
Emilio is going to hold a concert in Japan,
艾米利歐要在日本開演唱會耶
Conan.
柯南
Prince of Music, Emilio Baretti.
歌唱貴公子，艾米利歐·巴瑞帝
He's very famous in Japan too.
在日本也是超有人氣
My brother is finally here.
我弟他終於來了
Who's your brother?
誰是你弟？
Do you see that?
看到沒？
Yes.
看到了
Shocking, right?
很驚人對吧？
Is she his manager?
是經紀人嗎？
Such a beautiful lady, right?
超漂亮的美女姊姊
You are right!
就是說啊
Although they are still young, boys will still be boys.
雖然還小，但男生就是男生
They are losing their mind over a beautiful woman.
一見到美女，眼珠子都要掉下來了
No comment.
我不予置評
That's our live broadcast from Haneda Airport.
以上是來自羽田的現場連線
An extraordinary artist has arrived.
來了位相當轟動的明星呢
I didn't see it wrongly.
我沒有看錯
The person I saw just now is Daisuke Jigen.
剛才的人是次元大介
Even Conan is...
連柯南都…
Wait. What?
咦？什麼？
It's not like that.
不、不是啦
He's the worst.
那小子好差勁
I can't believe that.
真不敢相信
Come on.
你們…
You were looking at her!
你有在看!
I was not!
我沒有看!
This is the diamond that he has mistakenly stolen.
這就是他偷錯的鑽石
And these are the bullets from the crane he shot at.
以及打進吊車的子彈
Mistakenly stolen? Is that possible?
偷錯…有可能弄錯嗎？
It was Lupin's doing.
這些都是魯邦…
From disguising as Kiddo
無論是故意假扮基德
and stealing a diamond he's not interested in to him throwing it into a fisherman's bucket,
偷走根本不感興趣的鑽石 再扔進釣客水桶裡
we can be sure
這一切很篤定
that he was challenging us.
是他在對我們警方下戰帖
Challenging us.
戰帖…
I'm just kidding. That was not his plan.
才怪，他根本沒這個打算
He was just fooling around like usual,
這是他一貫的胡鬧嗎？
Inspector Zenigata?
錢形警部
His target this time
那傢伙這次的目標是
-is the well-known Cherry Sapphire. -He's from the ICPO...
- 聞名遐邇的「櫻桃藍寶石」 - 國際刑警組織的…
You know him right, Takagi?
高木老弟認得他吧？
The only inspector
國際刑警組織中
in the ICPO who is solely in charge of arresting Lupin III.
唯一一位魯邦三世專任搜查官
Hello, I am Zenigata.
各位好，我是錢形
Inspector.
警部
Does Lupin always fool around like that?
請問魯邦總是那樣把人耍著玩嗎？
Yes.
沒錯
You should just treat this incident as a normal occurrence.
勸各位要以平常心來看待這件事
How do you determine
那麼又是根據什麼判定
that the Cherry Sapphire is his real target?
櫻桃藍寶石是他的真正目標？
That's right. Maybe he's just fooling around again.
就是說啊，說不定又是在耍人
He sent me a mail.
他有寄mail來
He sent you a mail?
他、他會寄mail給你？
Yes. But I can't reply to it.
會啊，不過無法回信
They are pen pals?
他們還是筆友啊
Do you want to see it?
要看嗎？
-I do.
- 我要 - 我想看
Please control yourself.
你們稍微克制一下
Inspector Megure.
目暮警部
Can I borrow someone from here?
方便從這裡面借用人手嗎？
I don't mind, but I don't know if they'll be fit for the job.
我是不介意 就是不知道他們能不能勝任…
Fit for the job?
勝任？
Are you saying that we can join the operation to arrest Lupin?
意思是可以加入緝捕魯邦嗎？
This is supposed to be Division 2's mission.
這本來是搜查二課的任務
Inspector Nakamori is still in suspension.
但目前中森警部還在閉門思過
It's because of the mess he had caused in Tsukishima.
因為月島行動一塌糊塗啊
Then...
那…
As an exception, someone from Division 1...
就破例從一課派幾個人
Me!
我！我！我！我！
Me, too!
我…我也要！
I never thought
沒想到
that I would be lucky enough to participate in the operation to arrest Lupin.
我竟然有幸能參與追捕魯邦
Lupin III is Detective Sato's first love.
魯邦三世還是佐藤警官的初戀呢
Takagi.
高木
I see. That's why you were the first to raise your hand.
原來如此，所以才會第一個舉手
That's not the reason.
不…不是的
I didn't volunteer for this out of selfish gain.
我會志願參加並不是出於私心…
It doesn't matter.
有什麼關係
I'm sure you don't want your first love
逮捕初戀對象
to be arrested by other people.
應該不會想讓其他人搶先吧
I'll look forward to your performance.
期待妳的表現
Inspector Zenigata,
錢形警部
I will do my best.
我會努力的
I'm in love with Lupin as well in a way.
就某方面來說，我也愛著魯邦啊
This is so funny. How could someone park his car here?
真是笑死人了，竟然把車停在這裡
I'll teach him a lesson about the consequences of provoking the Traffic Division.
就讓他明白對交通部挑釁 會有什麼下場
Why can't we verify his plate number?
為什麼會查無車牌呢？學姊
Looks like it's not a simple fake license plate.
看來並不是單純的偽造車牌
Maybe the car belongs to a criminal organization.
有可能是什麼不法組織吧
It has a suspicious aura.
一整個不法到爆
I don't think people say that anymore.
現在沒人會用這種說法了吧？
Really?
沒人用了嗎？
You parked your car here?
您把車子停在這裡？
Yes.
嗯…
-It is Interpol's official car. (Visit the Traffic Division on 2F!)
到2樓的交通部來！
-Our Traffic Division doesn't care about that.
日本的交通部可不管那些 到2樓的交通部來！
-I'm sure this is Miyamoto and Miike's doing. (Visit the Traffic Division on 2F!)
是宮本、三池開的單
-I'll go to the Traffic Division now! -(Visit the Traffic Division on 2F!)
我這就去一趟交通部 到2樓的交通部來！
-Looks like I've been fined.
要繳罰金了…
Sonoko.
園子
Hello. What is it?
喂？什麼事？
-The TV? Right now? -Welcome to Japan.
- 電視？現在？ - 歡迎來到日本
-Do you like any Japanese food? -Yes. I'm watching it.
- 請問您有喜歡的日本食物嗎？ - 嗯…我正在看
Natto.
納豆
Let's meet him after school tomorrow.
明天放學後就去見他吧
Yes. Emilio. In the flesh.
對，艾米利歐，他本人
I know which hotel he's staying at.
我查到他住哪家飯店了
Really?
真的假的
How did you find that out?
妳怎麼查出來的？
I just made a good use of the intelligence network of my family's company.
只要善用我們財團的情報網
It was a piece of cake.
還不手到擒來
Really? But isn't that personal information?
善用…但那不是個人資料嗎？
No problem. Okay. I'll meet you there.
沒問題，OK，就約在那裡
Okay. See you tomorrow.
那就…嗯，明天見
The manager looks really pretty.
經紀人長得可真美
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼啊
I can't believe Sonoko.
園子也真是的
We could have discussed homework tomorrow.
作業明天再討論也可以啊
You found a way to meet Emilio?
有辦法見到艾米利歐嗎？
I can't believe you.
真受不了
Such a beauty!
大美人耶
He's on the same level as Genta and the others.
跟元太他們同等級啊
I'm coming with you, too!
我也要去
Is that really necessary?
有必要派出那個嗎？
He often escapes in a helicopter.
他常利用直升機脫逃
So, we are going to shoot it down?
常…所以準備要擊落嗎？
Is this really okay?
真的沒問題嗎？
Maybe we should move it...
還是移往他處比較…
I think it's better to keep it here.
我認為留在這裡會比較妥當
The more times we relocate it,
移動次數越多
the more chances for Lupin to steal it.
只會給予魯邦更多下手的機會
You are good.
果然厲害
Both of you. Follow me to the vault.
你們兩個跟我到金庫室去
-Roger that.
是
I'll come with you.
我…我也一起
This is the vault?
這就是那個金庫啊
Have you contacted the owner of the sapphire?
和藍寶石的主人取得聯絡了嗎？
Yes.
是的
We had suggested him to relocate it elsewhere.
本行也有建議可暫時移往他處保管
But Mr. Eishin Wakagomo...
但若護茂英心老先生他…
There's no need to do that.
沒那個必要
I trust our police.
我相信日本警方的能耐
Looks like you are well-trusted.
你們還真是備受信賴啊
We have to arrest him!
我們一定要逮到他
Leave it to us.
就包在我們身上
Am I right, Detective Sato?
對吧？佐藤警官
Calm down.
你冷靜一點
All of you!
各位
Let's be united and do our best together!
我們就團結一致、攜手努力吧
-Yes!
好！
This is so embarrassing. Please calm down.
這樣好丟臉，拜託你先靜下來
Five more minutes until Lupin's
距離魯邦預告的犯案時間
showtime.
還有5分鐘
All streets are in lockdown.
所有道路皆已封鎖
No vehicles will be allowed to pass from now on.
即刻起禁止車輛通行
All of you should change your communication frequency to channel B
除了行內戒備人員
except the security personnel inside the bank.
一律改以B頻道聯絡
Has Lupin ever been unpunctual before?
魯邦之前曾經不守時過嗎？
No.
不曾
In other words, there's only one minute left.
也就是說，再過1分鐘…
He must be nearby then.
所以他人應該就在附近
Yes.
是啊
He might have disguised himself as someone else to enter this place.
有可能會易容成某個人潛進來
Who?
是…是誰？
Detective Sato, don't do this!
佐藤警官，別這樣
Don't move. I'll shoot.
不准動，我會開槍的
He won't disguise himself as a human.
他不一定會易容成人類
He can disguise himself as non-human things?
人…人類之外也會？
He can do that?
他也有辦法易容嗎？
For instance, that vault door might be him in disguise.
假設那扇門就是魯邦偽裝的…
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I just wanted to ease the tension here.
我只是想讓大家放鬆一下
I wanted to see if I could make you laugh.
看能不能讓大家笑一下…
It's already after 1 pm.
已經過1點了
Nothing happened.
什…什麼事都沒有發生
Has he changed his plan because the security is too tight?
因為戒備太過森嚴而改變計劃？
He'll never give up on a target.
看中的獵物絕不放過
That's Lupin III.
這就是魯邦三世
So, Lupin
這就表示…
is already inside the vault?
魯邦人已經在金庫室裡頭了？
It's showed in movies.
電影裡頭不是也演過
The story where the thieves dig a tunnel underneath the vault
直接挖地道到金庫室正下方
and transport everything out.
再將物品偷出的劇情
Any CCTV cameras inside?
裡面有監視器嗎？
Privacy is important for Kashi Bank.
出租金庫畢竟得注重個人隱私…
As a precaution, open the vault.
為求謹慎，就打開來看看吧
Looks like there's no underground tunnel.
看來…並沒有被鑿出通道
I'm so relieved.
太好了
But,
不…不過
maybe the Cherry Sapphire has already been...
也有可能櫻桃藍寶石早就被…
Are you saying that it might have been stolen?
你想說它已經被偷走了是嗎？
How is that possible?
怎…怎麼會
It can't be!
不會吧
You have both of the keys?
兩把鑰匙都在你身上嗎？
Yes. Mr. Eishin had entrusted them to me.
是的，英心老先生有交給我保管
It's still here. The Cherry Sapphire is safe.
它還在，櫻桃藍寶石平安無事
Three minutes have passed.
距離預告的時間已經過了3分鐘
Could it be
說不定，說不定
that all of your watches are three minutes ahead?
大家的手錶都快了3分鐘？
It's one o'clock right now.
現在正好1點
I see now. You did it at that time.
我知道了，是那個時候
You disguised as Takagi
你易容成高木
and adjusted the time on our watches to three minutes later.
將大家的手錶轉快3分鐘吧
That is correct!
正確！正確！完全正確
The time is just right.
時間正好
I'll take this, Old Man.
我就收下了，老爹
You need to recharge yourself sometimes.
你偶爾也需要休息充個電啦
Goodbye, my first love.
再見了，我的初戀
It's so painful.
好痛…
It's going to be broken.
要斷了…
Luckily, you are always very punctual.
幸好你每次都很準時
You should be happy to be arrested by a cute lady.
被可愛女生逮捕，開心吧
Old Man, you are so cunning.
老爹，你好詐
You know that I won't fight against a woman.
利用我不會對女孩子出手這點
Let me rewind the time back to three minutes earlier.
呃…往回轉3分鐘
Lupin III
魯邦三世
is arrested
下午1點2分
at 1:02 for theft.
因竊盜現行犯罪名遭到逮捕
Well done.
做得好
It's such a waste for you to be just a detective.
妳當刑警算是大材小用了
Sorry for ruining your good mood.
那個…抱歉打壞兩位愉悅的心情
What are you going to do? I won't hesitate to shoot if you move.
怎樣？敢亂動我可不會客氣
Lupin. She's a mean character.
魯邦，這位小姐是個狠角色喔
I pasted a silver sticker on the back of your watch.
我有在手錶背面貼上銀色貼紙
Is it still there?
還在嗎？
Sticker? It's still here. This is...
貼紙？還在啊，這個是…
The Shocky-Shock Sticker that I've invented.
我發明的吱吱叫貼紙
It's a little bit stronger than a stun gun.
威力比電擊槍稍微強上一點吧
I'm sorry, Miss.
抱歉了，警察小姐
You can take this back.
這個還妳
Stop right there!
你別想跑
Are you for real, Old Man?
真的假的，老爹
I'll shock you again then.
那就再送你一次
I'm sorry, Miss.
抱歉了，小姐
You are caught up in it, too.
把妳給捲進來
You scoundrel!
你這混蛋
Old Man, do you really think you are a zombie?
老爹…你當自己是彊屍嗎？
I don't want to hurt her by shocking you both again.
再來一次我怕小姐會有危險
Goodbye.
再見啦
Lupin.
魯…邦…
You're so scary.
很嚇人耶
It's Lupin! He's in the vault!
是魯邦！在金庫室裡！
-He has disguised himself as Inspector Zenigata. (Authorized Personnel Only)
他易容成錢形警部了 （非相關人員禁止進入）
It's Lupin!
是魯邦！
-There he is!   -Get him! -Catch him!
- 他承認了 - 抓住他 -大夥兒上
Strike Team!
攻堅！
Charge!
衝啊！
Yes. Go on in.
好、好，快進去、快進去
I'm not him!
混帳！不是我…
This is so painful! Stop!
痛死我了…我是真的
Lupin has showed up at the bank!
魯邦在銀行內現身
Lupin...
魯邦…
It's Lupin!
是魯邦！
He's the real Lupin!
這個才是真的！
We've caught the third Lupin.
逮捕第三名魯邦
The fourth Lupin is sitting outside of a tobacco store.
第四名魯邦在香煙攤出現
I think he's the fake one.
我認為那是假的
-I'm from the TV station! -I can't pull it off.
- 我是電視台人員啦 - 面具怎麼都拔不起來
Central Command.
司令總部
-Is there a way for us to distinguish him? -You look very suspicious.
- 請問有方法能夠分辨真偽嗎？ - 這身打扮十分可疑
I've found Lupin in Beika Park.
米花公園內發現一隻魯邦
It is attached to me.
黏著我不放
They are chasing after someone near Beika Station's north exit!
米花車站北口有一群警察正在追捕
I don't have any mask left.
面具用完了
Lupin has entered Beika Street.
魯邦進入米花商店街
Send someone to the south entrance!
派人至南側入口
Sorry for interrupting your shopping time.
抱歉打擾各位購物啦
Is your business doing well?
生意好嗎？
What are you...
你怎麼…
Is your knife sharp?
刀還利吧？
You are too slow. I'm talking about the fish.
反應太慢，我說的是魚啊
Take this! Squid! Octopus! Ink!
看我的！花枝！章魚！墨汁！
-Please stand back.   -It's dangerous here. -It's a terrifying world, right?
- 請往後退 - 這裡很危險 - 這社會還真是恐怖，老奶奶
-A fiendish is on the run! -You are so kind.
- 兇惡罪犯正在逃逸 - 你人真好
Would you like to meet my granddaughter?
願意和我孫女見個面嗎？
I have no time to waste.
我可沒時間在這兒磨蹭
Darn it!
可惡！
We are playing right into his hands!
全都被他耍得團團轉！
What should we do?
該怎麼辦好？
Call for more reinforcements?
請求更多支援嗎？
We'll do the opposite.
相反！
Call it off.
解除這裡的行動
He has already escaped.
他早就溜了
Where are you going?
您…您要上哪去？
My watch is fried.
我的錶燒焦了
I happen to like this watch.
虧我很喜歡這支錶
What?
咦？
We lost sight of Lupin.
我們跟丟魯邦了
Being a thief is all about legwork.
小偷果然還是得靠腳力
I'm really addicted to the fun of being chased.
就是戒不掉你追我跑的樂趣
I can't believe that.
還真是…
If you are not going to use a car or a helicopter,
既不用車也不用直升機的話
you'll have to come to Beika Station.
就得靠米花車站
But the police can put the station on lockdown at once.
可是，警方立刻就能封鎖車站
Moreover, the distance between the bank and the subway station
加上從銀行要到地下鐵車站
is too far.
距離又太遠…
That was what I thought.
我原本是這麼想的
But after checking the locations of the air vents and construction access doors...
不過後來查到通風口 與施工出入口的位置後…
Impressive, Miss.
了不起喔，小姐
I'm going to fall in love with you.
我都要愛上妳了
But you should let me go.
但還是先放我一馬吧
I need this.
我不能沒有這玩意兒
Don't go.
別…別走
We'll play together when you are feeling better.
等妳身體恢復了再一起玩吧
That tunnel ahead should be connected to the electric company.
前面應該是 通往電力公司的共同管溝
-What's wrong? -Someone is on the railroad 100 meters away from Beika Station.
- 怎麼了？ - 有人在鐵軌上 - 西米花車站前100公尺處
-Did we go over that person?   - I can't believe this. -I think we've hit someone.
- 輾過去了嗎？ -不會吧… - 疑似發生撞人意外…
Are you okay, Detective Sato?
妳沒事吧？佐藤警官
Takagi.
高木
Luckily, I made it in time.
幸好我有趕上
Please. Don't be so reckless.
拜託妳別這麼亂來
You sound so arrogant.
你好大的口氣
I'm not the one who had been subdued by Lupin.
這還不都…要怪某個人… 被魯邦制伏
Yes. I'm sorry. I was too careless.
是啊…對不起，我太大意了
I can't believe you.
真是的
I won't leave your side ever again.
我不會再離開妳身邊了
Really?
是嗎？
Handcuffs?
手銬？
You are Lupin, right?
你是魯邦對吧？
Takagi won't be like this.
高木才不會這樣
You saw right through me.
哎呀呀，被妳識破了啊
Stop right there, Lupin!
等…給我停下來，魯邦
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Did you hear Detective Sato's voice just now?
叔叔有聽到佐藤刑事的聲音嗎？
You must have heard it wrongly.
是你聽錯了吧
I'm sorry that my father is tagging along too.
抱歉喔，連我爸都跟來
It's okay.
沒關係啦
I'll feel creeped out if he's tagging along to meet Emilio,
如果他是想見艾米利歐 那我會起雞皮疙瘩
but he's here for the manager, right?
是要見那位經紀人對吧？
It'll be hard not to fall for her.
確實想不動心都難
We are here.
我們抵達了喔，小蘭公主
-Princess Ran. (Sakurasaku Hotel)
莎克拉莎克飯店
-Don't call me that.
妳別鬧我
So nostalgic.
總覺得好懷念喔
Actually, it hasn't been that long.
其實也沒過多久啊
You are right.
也對
Wait here. I'll get the manager.
等一下，我去叫經理出來
You'll go and get her?
要去叫人喔…
I'm the one who perfectly solved the attempted murder of the princess of Vespania Kingdom,
我是精彩解決 維斯帕尼亞公主毒殺未遂事件的
the Great Detective Kogoro Mouri.
名偵探毛利小五郎
Uncle, what are you doing?
叔叔，你在做什麼？
I'm sure my assistant has made an appointment.
我的助手應該有預約了
Assistant?
助手
What is he doing?
真是…爸他在做什麼啊
As if it would mean something to them.
突然說那些誰會知道
But looks like it works.
似乎意外地可行喔
I'll take it.
這裡我來就行了
Detective Mouri, let's talk elsewhere.
毛利偵探，這裡不方便說話
This way please.
這邊請
Okay.
那好吧
What is going on?
怎麼回事？
Let's go.
快走吧
Okay.
也好
Wait for me.
等等我
I don't care about Interpol.
國際刑警組織了不起啊
A violation is still a violation.
違規就是違規
No matter who he is, he still has to pay for the tow-away fee.
管他對方是誰，都一樣要繳拖吊費
It's the country's important source of income.
這可是重要的國庫財源呢
He should fetch the car himself.
有本事就自己來取車啊
I might put a dent on the car.
小心我把你車子弄凹
The key is inside the car, right?
鑰匙在車內對吧？
I heard that it's in the visor.
聽說是用遮陽板夾住
Does he think this is Europe?
當這裡是歐美嗎
Senpai, Detective Takagi is in the backseat.
學姊，高木警官倒在後座
What? How did that happen?
啊？怎麼會？
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
I'm all tied up.
我被人綁住了
Everyone is waiting for you in the conference room.
其他人已經在會議室恭候大駕
Sorry for making them wait.
讓大家久等啦
I feel bad.
真不好意思
Go left after you exit from the elevator.
出電梯後請往左手邊走
Okay.
好
This is the one.
就是這間
So nostalgic.
挺懷念的
Excuse me.
打擾了
Dad, you need to knock first.
爸，要先敲門
What's the result?
結果怎樣了？
Nothing.
沒事…
Inspector Shiratori?
白烏警部？
Mouri?
毛利老弟？
Inspector. Why are you here?
警部大人…你怎麼會在這裡？
Hello.
大家好
Is he here?
在嗎？在嗎？
Inspector Megure, who are they?
目暮警部，請問這幾位是？
Don't worry. He is...
不用擔心，這位是…
The greatest detective in Japan,
日本第一的名偵探
Kogoro Mouri, at your service.
屬於你的毛利小五郎
Hello, Miss.
小姐妳好
H-Hello.
是…
What?
奇怪…
Sorry for that.
失禮了
I am his daughter, Ran Mouri.
我是他的女兒，毛利蘭
I am his assistant, Sonoko Suzuki.
我是助手，鈴木園子
You can just call me Sonoko.
叫我園子就好
They are all the same.
全都是一個德行
Since Inspector Megure and the others are here, it means...
目暮警部他們在這裡就表示…
I get it now. The receptionist who knows Uncle Mouri
我懂了，認識叔叔的櫃台人員
brought us here because he mistakenly thinks that he's here for the case.
誤以為他是為了案件而來 才會帶我們來這裡
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎？
Not here.
與這裡無關
Inspector Megure.
目暮警部
Takagi is found unharmed.
高木平安被發現
But the Cherry Sapphire...
不過櫻桃藍寶石…
Lupin?
魯邦？
Lupin.
魯邦
Fujiko.
不二子
I was worried about you.
我好擔心妳說
Are you okay?
沒被人怎樣吧？
I'm fine. But I was terrified.
沒有，可是我嚇壞了
They've put such an ugly necklace on you.
還被人戴上毫無品味可言的項鍊
You have really bad taste.
你的品味很差耶
Let's get this over with.
儘快完成交易吧
Give it to Fujiko.
把東西交給不二子
You are so impatient.
性子還真急
You don't like to chat?
不愛跟人聊天？
Why are you like this?
幹嘛這樣
I won't pull out a gun.
我怎麼可能會掏把槍出來
Can't you read the situation? I can't believe this.
你們也看看狀況好嗎？真受不了
Forget about the box.
盒子就免了
I just want the Cherry Sapphire inside.
我只要裡頭的櫻桃藍寶石
I can't believe you. Why are you doing this?
真是的…這算什麼？
Looks like there's no trick.
看來他並沒有動什麼手腳
I'm sorry.
抱歉囉
You are indeed working together.
你們果然是一夥的
It looks real, right?
做得很逼真吧？
But it's fake. One more thing.
可惜是假的，還有…
I'm sorry, but I can't hand this to you.
不好意思，這可不會交給你
Okay?
OK吧？
Drop your weapons.
把武器全都扔了
That's Fujiko for you.
不愧是不二子
I really want to say that.
我是很想這麼說啦
But you've made a mistake this time.
但妳這次稍微輕忽了
What do you mean?
怎麼說？
No matter what it looks like, it's a real bomb.
那個炸彈怎麼看都是真的
You are lying to me.
騙人
How could you trick a weak woman? How terrible!
竟然欺騙弱女子，真差勁
Take it since you want it so much.
這麼想要就給你吧
What are we going to do next?
再來要怎樣？
You want to see my head being blown off from my body?
想看我當場身首異處是嗎？
Although my taste is being judged,
儘管我的品味似乎備受懷疑
this is considered a done deal.
如此一來交易就算完成
I will deactivate the bomb
確認我方安全無虞後
as soon as my safety is secure.
就會立刻解除炸彈
Of course. If I find out that it's a counterfeit...
當然，一旦發現這是贗品…
Don't worry. It's a real one.
不用擔心，是真的
What else?
不然呢
Don't tell me that this is another test.
可別說這又是另外一場測試
No. This is the last one.
不…這是最後了
You can have that SUV.
那輛休旅車就送給妳了
The coat inside is a present for you.
裡頭的大衣也是禮物
Thank you.
謝謝
I think we won't
我們應該…
see each other again.
不會再見了
(1F Exit of Sakurasaku Hotel)
（莎克拉莎克飯店 IF 出口）
He is the promoter of the concert in Japan,
這位是日本公演的主辦人
Mr. Carnevale Luciano.
盧奇亞諾·卡尼瓦瑞先生
Hello.
你好
And she is...
而這邊這位是…
I am Claudia Belucci.
我叫克勞蒂亞·貝露奇
I am Emilio's manager.
擔任艾米利歐的經紀人
I know that.
這我知道
We are all gathered here because...
我們之所以會齊聚在此…
Inspector.
警部
Is it fine to just disclose it?
說出來不會有問題嗎？
Although Mr. Mouri looks like this,
別看毛利先生這樣
you can trust him.
您大可以相信他
The first sentence is unnecessary.
前面那句話是多餘的
I believe that I can be useful to you.
我相信自己能夠派上用場
Well,
就是…
this morning, I received this letter addressed to Emilio.
今天早上 我收到這封署名給艾米利歐的信
This is...
這是…
What is
這上頭…
written on it?
寫了些什麼？
You had created such a suspense.
營造了這麼久的氣氛
But it turns out you can't read it at all.
其實根本看不懂啊
That's typical of him.
標準的叔叔風格
They are newspaper cut-outs. Is it written in Italian?
從報紙上剪下來…義大利文嗎？
Cancel the concert at once. Or else,
馬上取消演唱會，不然的話…
Emilio will die.
艾米利歐就會沒命
I can't believe this!
騙人
A threat letter?
恐嚇信？
He will die?
「就會沒命」…是嗎？
Who else has touched this letter?
接觸過這封信的人有…
I didn't touch it.
我沒有碰過
Emilio and I have touched it.
艾米利歐和我有拿過
If we find fingerprints that are not yours,
若是找到不屬於兩位的指紋
those must be the culprit's fingerprints.
就會是犯人的指紋
If the culprit left his fingerprints on the threat letter,
如果是會在恐嚇信上 留下指紋的犯人
it would be easy for us.
那倒是省事不少
Let's cancel it.
取消吧
I don't want to die!
我可不想死
We can just cancel the concert, right?
只要取消演唱會不就行了？
Calm down, Emilio.
冷靜點，艾米利歐
We can't just cancel it so easily.
不要輕易把取消掛在嘴邊
We've invested a lot of money into this concert in Japan.
這次的日本公演已經投入龐大資金
We even rushed Touto Stadium to complete their reconstruction.
還要求東都體育館趕工完成改建
Moreover, all of the tickets are sold out.
再者門票早就銷售一空
We can't just cancel it now.
到這個節骨眼上哪能輕易喊停
You know that, right?
你心裡也明白吧
Please, Lupin.
拜託你囉，魯邦
Or else, this necklace will explode.
不然這玩意兒就會爆炸說
Take this job if you love me.
愛人家的話就接下這個工作
Enough. Stop mocking me.
真是的，別挖苦我了
I know that I brought this on myself.
就直接說我是自作自受嘛
No. What I'm angry about is what you said next.
不，該罵的是接下來的內容
Forget it then. I'll ask Kiddo for help.
那就算了，人家會去拜託基德大人
That was because...
那是因為…
Do you really understand?
妳真的有弄懂嗎？
Understand what?
弄懂什麼？
There's only one person in this world
能夠保護不二子的人
who can protect you.
這世上只有一個…
Who is it?
是誰啊？
Lupin.
魯邦…
That's right! Let's go on a recline!
沒錯！座椅往後躺！
No.
不行
Why?
為什麼？
Run away now. Or else...
你快逃，要不然…
Wouldn't it be great if I could go to the afterlife
能和妳一起到另一個世界去
with you?
也是極樂
That man.
那傢伙
How dare he tricked me.
敢欺騙我會有什麼下場
I'll make him pay.
絕對要讓他後悔莫及
Fujiko, give me back my clothes.
不二子，衣服還我啊
Are you sure we should deactivate it?
解除是正確的嗎？
If we kill that woman,
要是殺了那個女的
Lupin will be hot on our tails.
魯邦將會對我們窮追猛打
We can't let that happen now.
目前還不行
For my country, I have to get it.
為了祖國…我非弄到手不可
Mr. Emilio's stay in this hotel
艾米利歐先生下榻這間飯店的事
is not announced to public.
並未對外公開
Only the staff of the concert and some of the hotel personnel
知道此事的就只有演唱會工作人員
know about this.
與部分飯店員工
But we can't eliminate the possibility of outsiders, too.
但也不能因此排除外人犯案的可能
His hardcore fans will do everything they can
狂熱的歌迷會用盡一切手段
to find out where he stays.
查出他的投宿地點
Although this might be a prank,
雖然這很可能是一場惡作劇
I'll send some undercover police to guard your safety.
我們會派便衣警察站崗
We'll observe first.
先觀察一陣子…
I know who's the culprit.
我知道犯人是誰了
Really, Mouri?
真…真的嗎？毛利老弟
Yes. The person who sent the threat letter is
對，寄出那封恐嚇信的人就是…
Lupin III.
魯邦三世
Lupin?
魯邦？
Are you for real?
你講真的嗎？叔叔
He's the thief
就是前天開始
who had disrupted the city two days ago.
接連在市內造成混亂的小偷
He put in so much effort to steal the jewel
大費周章把寶石偷到手
and threw it away after that.
隨即又扔掉
It was probably not good enough for him.
想必是看不上眼吧
Just now, you received a call about
剛才的電話是在回報
another jewel being stolen by Lupin, right? Shiratori.
又有寶石被魯邦偷走了對吧？白鳥
What happened to him? He's so sharp today.
叔叔是吃錯藥啦？表現好犀利喔
We did receive a report just now.
我們剛才的確有收到回報
How is that related to this threat letter?
那跟這封恐嚇信有什麼關聯嗎？
The reason Lupin
讓演唱會被迫取消
stole the precious jewel and wanted the concert to be canceled is...
竊得貴重寶石的魯邦目的想必是…
What's the reason?
想必是？
Claudia-san.
克勞蒂亞小姐
He wants to
他想趁妳情緒低落時
give that jewel to you when you are down.
再將寶石送給妳
Give her the jewel?
送給她？
That's right! He's trying to pursue you!
沒錯！那傢伙打算要追求妳！
It's too dangerous here. Please stay with me for your safety.
這裡太危險了，請務必移到寒舍
Emilio.
艾米利歐
Don't worry. I won't leave my room.
別擔心，我不會離開房間
I haven't gotten his signature.
我還沒要到簽名耶
Let's go back, Sonoko.
回去吧，園子
Now is not the time to ask for his signature.
現在可不是要簽名的時候
Conan, let's go.
柯南，我們走吧
Okay.
好
What about your father?
叔叔呢？
It'll be impossible to move him when he's like that.
陷入那種狀態的他，難喔
You are right.
也對
Anyway, I'll send someone to guard this floor.
總之，先派人在這層樓戒備吧
I think they'll be fine.
應該沒問題啦
They already have a reliable bodyguard.
他已經有個超可靠的保鑣了
How do you know, little boy?
小弟弟，你竟然會知道
I saw him on TV.
我在電視上看到的
Conan.
柯南
Coming.
來了
A reliable bodyguard?
可靠的保鑣是嗎？
I heard that with his military education, he tripled the military power of a country.
據說光靠他對軍人進行教育 就讓某國軍事能力變成三倍
He's an instructor with charisma.
是位領導力非凡的教官
Papa is so amazing.
爸爸好厲害喔
We'll get going now.
我們先走了
There's a dessert cafe downstairs, right?
樓下有一家甜點餐廳對吧？
Yes. You have a sharp eye.
有啊有啊，妳的眼睛還真利
We should visit it before we go back.
吃完再回去？
Sure.
嗯，好啊
I think it's above the lobby.
記得是在大廳的上一層
Yes.
嗯
Huh? Where's Conan?
咦？柯南？
Hurry up! Or we'll leave you behind, you brat!
快點！我們要扔下你囉，小鬼頭
Please don't leave me behind.
拜託不要扔下我
Let's have fun together.
我們一起去玩吧
Wait, but...
等…可是…
You look so handsome, brat.
小、小鬼頭長得可真好
Sonoko, that's not it.
園子，不對啦
This is a miracle!
奇蹟發生了！
Sonoko!
園子！
(Smoking Area)
（吸煙區）
Wait for a moment.
先等一下…
I'm in
我現在…
the embrace of Emilio now.
被艾米利歐攬在懷裡…
And we are running together.
一起奔跑著
Wait. Please wait.
等一下，拜託先等一下
Stop right now.
先給我停下來
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Listen to me, Sonoko. Think about it carefully.
聽好了，園子，妳先好好想一想
Aren't you going to check on me first?
不先問我「還好嗎？」嗎？
We have to go back.
要回去才對
He can't leave this place.
這種時候不能外出吧
Why?
為什麼？
What do you mean why? He received a threat letter.
什麼為什麼，都收到恐嚇信了耶
If something happens to Emilio...
要是艾米利歐有個萬一…
It's obviously just a prank.
那很明顯只是惡作劇啦
How can you be so sure?
哪能這麼武斷
The letter stated that he'll die.
上頭還寫了，會沒命的
I didn't see it.
我又沒看到
Stop fooling around.
妳別鬧了
You defeated the strongest guards in the Vespania Kingdom, right?
維斯帕尼亞王國最厲害的保鑣 都被妳撂倒了不是嗎？
Don't exaggerate.
別說得這麼誇張
At any rate, no one within this 10 km can defeat you.
總之，半徑10公里內妳所向披靡
Sonoko.
園子…
There! Let's go there!
那裡！我們去那裡吧！
Okay! We can go anywhere you want.
好的，去哪裡都好
We'll definitely
一定…
get lectured for this!
會挨罵啦！
Do you want to pollute your clean lungs?
想汙染你乾淨的肺嗎？
This is the only place where you can smoke and drink at the same time in this hotel.
這間飯店裡就只有這裡可以 同時抽煙又喝酒
Fine. You win, great detective.
算你行，名偵探
Excuse me, this place is...
這位客人，這裡…
I'm here to get my Papa.
我是來接爸爸回去的
I see. Do you want a glass of juice?
這樣啊，那要來杯果汁嗎？
Give me a cup of ice coffee.
來杯冰咖啡
Right away.
我明白了
What is it?
怎樣？
You are not the only one who drinks ice coffee
一年四季都喝冰咖啡的人
throughout the four seasons.
又不是只有你
Why are you in this city?
你們來這座城市有什麼企圖？
You are back to being Shinichi Kudo.
改成工藤新一的口氣啦
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
Please try out this lemon pie too.
另外要請您品嚐這份檸檬派
Thank you.
謝謝
Looks like it's quite hard for you too.
你也挺辛苦的嘛
Scoundrel.
混帳
Your pet phrase is "scoundrel"?
口頭禪是「混帳」啊
Another phrase is, "I need to use the toilet".
還有「我去一下廁所」
Why do you have a memo of me?
幹嘛做那種筆記
If you go to the toilet so often at this young age,
年紀輕輕就這麼勤跑廁所
you should get it checked out.
去看一下醫生吧
You know that's not the reason.
你明知不是那樣
Do you get it now?
曉得了吧…
Adults are scary.
大人是很可怕的
You are threatening me.
你這是在恐嚇我
Don't worry.
用不著擔心
Everything will be peaceful as long as you stay out of it.
只要你別插手，一切就會風平浪靜
Don't you have this in your memo?
你的筆記上沒有寫嗎？
Threatening me will only spur me on.
我只要被恐嚇就會更燃起鬥志
You are so annoying.
有夠麻煩的
I'll take the pie.
派就給我吃囉
You called me "Papa" just now, right?
你剛才喊我「爸爸」對吧？
You are so slow.
太慢說了吧
It's me.
是我
What is it, Ran-neechan?
怎麼啦？小蘭姊姊
Emilio is gone?
艾米利歐不見了？
You are with Emilio?
妳跟艾米利歐在一起？
Why aren't you with him?
你怎麼沒跟在他身邊？
Sonoko is with me too.
還有園子也在
Everyone is looking for him.
大家都在找他
We'll go back after we visit the tower. Tell my father and the others...
我們說好登完塔之後就會回去 你跟爸爸他們…
Okay. I'll be keeping this for you.
好，這個由我保管
No. Give it back to me.
不行，快還我
Wait...
你怎麼…
Looks like you are having fun.
玩得挺開心的嘛
Okay. I got it.
好…知道了
The call that you were on...
聽你那通電話…
This is delicious.
真好喝
Looks like they are with Emilio.
他們似乎是跟艾米利歐在一起
I think so.
好像吧
Where are they?
在哪裡？
I don't know.
不知道
Now is the time to talk like an adult.
這種時候就該用成年人的方式交涉
I have to go now.
我要走囉
Fine.
好啦好啦
I'll tear this memo to pieces.
這份筆記我這就把它撕碎
Look. I throw it away.
你看，全都扔掉了喔
You should stick close to Papa, right?
爸爸跟你陪不是
It's going up so quickly!
好快
This is amazing.
好驚人
Can we really do this?
這樣好嗎？
What was the bodyguard doing?
保鑣是在做什麼？
It's pointless to play the blaming game now.
現在說這些也沒用
Let's start with the places nearby.
我們就先從附近找起吧
The police have left, right?
刑警他們已經離開了吧？
Yes, but that detective is still here.
是的，不過那位偵探還沒走
Has he left to search for him?
去找人了嗎？
Yes.
是的
What a useless bodyguard!
真是沒用的保鑣
Sorry about that,
真是抱歉囉
but I'll have to leave after this is done.
不過事情辦完後 我可是要先告辭了
If it's in the hotel, it'll be around here.
有的話就會在這裡…
What a beautiful sunset!
美麗的夕陽
With a handsome man!
加上帥哥
Ran. You look so scary.
小蘭，表情很恐怖喔
This won't do. Everyone looks suspicious.
不行啊，每個人看起來都好可疑
Let's go back.
我們回去了啦
Although it's not that possible,
雖然可能性不大…
I should check here too.
這邊也調查一下吧
Even the shoes are altered.
竟然連鞋子都換了
It's me.
是我
You are right. It's not in the hotel.
猜的沒錯，不在飯店裡
I think it's hidden in the concert's equipment.
嗯，應該就是演唱會器材了
What are you doing?
幹嘛？
You have to ask?
還問我幹嘛
Didn't I tell you to go to the tower first?
我不是要你先去塔那裡嗎
I want to go with Papa.
我想跟爸爸一起去嘛
You liar.
小騙子
Will the bodyguard be in charge of the spare key?
保鑣會負責保管備用鑰匙嗎？
I didn't steal anything. The police have no reason to arrest me.
我什麼都沒偷，警察能抓我嗎？
Having a gun with you will be a good enough reason.
光是持有槍械這點就夠了吧
Since I'm your Papa, let me give you a piece of advice.
看在父子情誼的份上奉勸你一句
This has nothing to do with you. How about you turn a blind eye to this?
這次的事跟你們毫無關係 就睜一隻眼閉一隻眼如何？
Answer me.
快回答
No.
不要
Onee-san.
大姊姊
What is it, little boy?
是，小弟弟，什麼事？
Do you have any newspapers in Italian?
請問有義大利文的報紙嗎？
I'm sorry. We only provide newspapers in English here.
抱歉，我們飯店只有提供英文報紙
Do you need it now?
現在就要嗎？
No. It's okay. Thank you.
不，沒關係，謝謝妳
Excuse me.
那個…不好意思
What is it, darling?
什麼事？親愛的
-I need to go there. (Men's Restroom)
男廁
-Go ahead.
請…請慢走 男廁
You are slow to call.
喂，你的電話來得還真慢
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Yes.
嗯
I've heard about Lupin's theft.
我有聽說魯邦引起的騷動
He stole the Cherry Sapphire
遭竊的是櫻桃藍寶石
that was originally kept in the vault of Kashi Bank, a bank in Touto.
原本寄放在東都銀行的出租金庫
Anything special about that jewel?
那顆寶石有什麼來頭嗎？
No. It's nothing special.
沒有，沒什麼特別的啊
I can't find any clues on the internet, either.
網路搜尋也毫無線索
But Lupin went as far as sending an advanced notice.
會讓魯邦發出預告…
I got it. It's about the owner of the jewel.
我知道了，是寶石的擁有者
Bingo.
答對了
Finally, you've caught up to Kojima and the others.
你終於趕上小嶋他們了
Caught up? Don't tell me that they are investigating it, too?
趕上…他們該不會又
They are very serious about it. More than ever.
非常投入呢，超乎以往
They've been investigating all the vacant buildings, bushes, and basements
從早上就一一查訪市內的空屋
in the city since this morning.
還有草叢和大樓地下室
Are they trying to locate Lupin's secret hideout?
該不會是想找出魯邦的祕密基地？
If they could find it, we wouldn't need the police.
要是找得到就不需要警察了
They found it.
找到了啊
Really?
真的假的
The owner of Cherry Sapphire, Eishin Wakagomo.
櫻桃藍寶石的擁有者，若護茂英心
Will someone rich enough to rent a vault
有能力使用銀行出租金庫的人
live in an abandoned repair shop?
會住在倒閉的維修廠內？
Furthermore, the shutters at the entrance were recently renewed.
而且入口的鐵捲門似乎最近才翻新
They are already so far into it?
他們查到這麼深入了？
The professor is excited, too.
博士也興致勃勃
Professor.
博士…
I can't stop them by myself.
靠我一個根本阻止不了
This is too dangerous.
太危險了
Don't let them leave the house before I get there!
在我趕到前別讓他們出門
This is too much.
真是夠了
After we capture Lupin, let's travel to Hawaii!
抓到魯邦換夏威夷之旅吧
-Great!
好！
Impossible.
不可能啦
We'll be featured on TV, right?
這樣會上電視吧
What is it?
什麼事？
I forgot to tell you what I needed you to search for me.
忘記說我要妳查的事了
Emilio's manager and promoter.
艾米利歐的經紀人和主辦人
Okay.
嗯…
Okay. I'll check on it.
是，了解，我會去查
What are you planning...
那你打算…
How rude!
有夠任性
Have you found him?
有找到嗎？
No.
沒有
Has he gone down?
先下去了嗎？
He pretended to enter the restroom.
他是假裝走進去吧
And I didn't take my eyes off the restroom after that.
那之後我眼睛就沒離開過
He had planned to ditch us since the beginning.
他打一開始就準備要自己開溜
Why?
怎麼說？
I don't know. But we have to find him first.
我也不曉得…總之先找再說
Okay.
嗯
(Do Not Enter)
（禁止進入）
Was it really Emilio?
真的是艾米利歐？
What?
咦？
He's not here.
沒有啊
I'm sure it was him.
是他本人沒錯
Will he come here all by himself?
艾米利歐會獨自外出嗎？
You saw Emilio?
你們有看到艾米利歐是嗎？
Who are you?
請問您是？
I'm a member of his Japan Tour staff.
我是他日本巡迴演唱會的工作人員
It was really him.
果然是他本人沒錯
You are so cute.
妳長得真可愛
After hearing that, I went to take an autograph board.
聽他這麼說，我就跑去拿簽名板了
During working hours?
上班時間耶
Miss.
小姐
You can't enter!
那邊禁止進入
Get the chief.
快找主任過來
You are so slow.
有夠慢
I'm sorry.
抱歉、抱歉
I need to buy a ticket.
我得買票才行
Here you go.
拿去
You are so kind.
你人真好
Don't mock me.
別酸我
What are you doing, Emilio?
你在做什麼？艾米利歐
Ran-san.
小蘭小姐
You can't come here.
妳不可以跑來這種地方喔
Please. Stop fooling around.
拜託你別再鬧了
Don't come here!
不要過來！
Tell me. Why are you doing this?
拜託你告訴我…為什麼要這麼做
I hate the concert.
我討厭開演唱會
Is that so? You are exhausted.
是嗎…你累了啊
It's okay. You can take a good rest.
沒關係啊，你可以好好休息
Impossible!
不可能的
As long as I'm alive, the concert won't be canceled.
只要我還在，演唱會就不可能取消
How is this possible?
怎、怎麼會…
This is not right.
未免也太奇怪了吧
How can a concert be more important than a person's life?
演唱會怎麼可能 會比人命來得重要！
If they are not willing to cancel it,
如果他們不願意取消
I'll...
那就由我…由我來…
Anyway, I beg you. Please come back here!
總之算我求你，先從那邊走回來
We are the only ones here.
就只有我們耶
We are the only ones who will go up at this time.
這麼晚了還要到上頭去
Are they still up there?
不過他們人在上面嗎？
They didn't tell me that they'd gone down.
我並沒有接到已經下去的聯絡喔
Do you have
這個城市裡也有
a secret hideout in this city?
爸爸你們的祕密基地嗎？
Don't think that I'll answer you just because you talk like a kid.
別以為用小孩子口吻問話 我就會有問必答
You do have a hideout.
有啊
How do you come to that conclusion?
你這是哪來的結論
You can't do this.
這樣…這樣是不行的
Please. Tell me
拜託你將一切…
about everything.
都告訴我吧
I...
我…
Emilio.
艾米利歐
Hold on to me!
抓住我的手
Ran-san, I...
小蘭小姐，我…
I'm fine.
我沒問題
Can you reach there with your feet?
有辦法把腳踩到那邊嗎？
Yes.
好
Ran!
小蘭！
Sonoko.
園子…
Don't make such a pathetic sound.
別發出這麼窩囊的聲音
Ran Mouri is an incredible person.
毛利蘭可是很了不起的
I'll pull you up in one go!
一鼓作氣往上拉！
Ready...
預備…
No!
不行！
It's dangerous.
危險
Sonoko?
園子？
Ran!
小蘭！
Uncle, can you open up a hole here?
大叔，可以開個洞嗎？
The lady who is hanging here?
掛在那裡的是那位小姐？
Yes.
對
How thick is this?
厚度多少？
Two 10mm glass panels.
10mm的2片
How big do you want it to be?
要開多大？
Big enough for me to fit.
讓我出得去
It'll take 12 shots.
要12發
Ran, don't let go of Emilio's hand!
小蘭，千萬別鬆開艾米利歐的手
I'm going to slap him
我要賞他巴掌
for putting my best friend through this.
竟然讓我最好的朋友遇到這種事
Who does he think he is?
他以為他是誰啊
I'm going to beat him into a pulp!
我一定要把他打到變豬頭為止
Sonoko.
園子…
Is this enough?
可以嗎？
I'm sorry, Sonoko.
抱歉…園子…
Wait...
等…
I think I'm out of strength.
我好像已經…沒有力…
Ran!
小蘭…
Ran-neechan!
小蘭姊姊！
Brat!
小鬼頭
Conan-kun.
柯南
Thank you, Conan-kun.
謝謝你，柯南
You are amazing!
了不起！
You are amazing, brat!
太了不起了！小鬼頭
I'll give you a hug later!
晚點我再給你個擁抱
I'll pass.
這個就免了
Sir, what are you doing?
先…先生，請問您這是在做什麼？
What am I doing?
做什麼…
Saving someone's life.
不就是救人一命囉
They are fine. Don't worry.
他們兩個都好得很，不需要擔心
Not only you put yourself in danger,
你…不光是讓自己
you even dragged other people into it.
甚至還讓周遭的人陷入險境
Do you know how serious this is?
你知道事情的嚴重性嗎？
Please think about it carefully.
請你好好想一想
Are you willing to help us?
妳願意…幫助我們嗎？
Don't worry. I won't cancel the concert.
不用擔心，演唱會不可能取消
That's good.
那就好
The idol working for you is such a showoff.
你旗下的那個偶像 會不會太出鋒頭了
If he attracts too much attention,
萬一太過引人側目
I'm afraid that it'll obstruct our transaction.
我怕反而會妨礙到交易
Did you call just to talk about this?
你打來就是為了說這個？
It is an unnecessary risk.
這樣反而會引發不必要的風險
Yes. Let's stick to the time and place we said earlier.
對，地點與時間一切照舊
Does Claudia-san know about it, too?
克勞蒂亞小姐也知道嗎？
Yes.
她知道
She's willing to help him despite knowing it since the beginning.
她從一開始就知道卻還是願意協助
A secret transaction of what?
暗中交易…是在交易什麼？
I don't know.
我不知道
While we are doing our live performance on the stage,
我們在舞台上進行演唱的時候
I'm sure that during that time...
一定是趁那時候…
It happened after Luciano became the promoter, right?
是從那個叫盧奇亞諾的人 擔任主辦人後才開始的吧？
Yes.
對…
And then, everything changed.
然後一切都變了
No matter it's the song, the stage
無論是歌曲、舞台
or the attitude of the TV stations towards us.
還是電視台對我們的態度
At first, they wouldn't even listen to our demo tapes.
本來對試聽帶都不屑一顧
But the one who has changed the most
但變最多的…
is Claudia.
是克勞蒂亞吧
She's happier than anyone else.
她比任何人都要開心
She loves my songs more than anyone.
比任何人都深愛著我的歌
You thought that the transaction will fall through
你認為只要取消演唱會
if the live concert is canceled.
交易就會跟著化為泡影
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
I didn't mean to jump down.
我並沒有要往下跳的意思
I had misunderstood you.
是我誤會你了
I'm sorry for hitting you.
抱歉還動手打了你…
I understand.
我都明白的
You were mad because you cared about me.
妳是真心為我好才會動怒
I'm sorry that I forgot to give this back to you.
抱歉，忘記還妳了
Yeah.
就是說啊
Dad.
爸爸
Hello?
喂？
Yes. I know.
嗯…我知道
He's with me now.
他現在跟我在一起
Don't shout so loudly.
真是的，別那麼大聲啦
Look at this piece of paper.
看一下這張紙片
I found it in your room.
就掉在你的房間裡
Why would it be in my room?
我的房間裡怎麼會…
Don't try to hide it.
你就不要再隱瞞了
There's no Italian newspaper in that hotel.
那間飯店並沒有提供義大利文報紙
Claudia-san could read the content of the letter
克勞蒂亞小姐毫無疑問地
without any difficulties.
就看出恐嚇信的內容
So, it means
這就表示
that this "K" is not from the letter.
這個「K」並不是從信裡頭脫落的
You are right.
說的也是
If it fell out when the letter was opened,
如果是開信的時候脫落
everyone would notice it.
應該會注意到才對
There are faint cutting marks on the table.
桌上有留下淺淺的割痕
You used a cutter to cut them out, right?
你是用美工刀對吧？
We don't typically use the letter "K" in the Italian language.
義大利文基本上不會用到字母K
I can destroy the evidence,
湮滅證據
right?
可以吧？
Luxury hotels won't throw away the trash so quickly.
高級飯店不會立刻將垃圾處理掉
When you go back, you have to hide the cutter and the newspaper.
回去之後 得馬上把美工刀和報紙藏起來才行
I even threw away the glue.
我連膠水都一起扔了
Police in Japan are very good in their job.
日本警察可是很厲害的
You were acting like this at the tower, too.
剛才在塔上也是…
Who are you?
你究竟…是什麼人？
Conan Edogawa.
江戶川柯南
I'm a detective.
是個偵探
Is that your catchphrase?
那句是你的固定說法？
I'll copy it.
偷來用好了
You are really amazing.
你…真了不起
A lot of your fans are waiting for you.
有好多歌迷在等著
Make the live concert a success.
你要讓演唱會成功
I'll stop the transaction.
我絕對會阻止交易
And I'll arrest all of the bad guys.
並且將壞蛋們全都繩之以法
I've been searching a long time for you.
我找你好久了
How can you be out here at this time?
這種時候怎麼能跑到外頭來
Do you know how worried I was?
你知不知道我有多擔心？
Do you know how much trouble you had caused?
你知道自己給多少人造成困擾嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
I don't know what would happen if it weren't for you, Mr. Mouri.
要不是毛利先生找到他 情況不曉得會變怎麼樣
Don't mention it.
用不著謝
Tracking people down is a basic requirement in this line of job.
尋人是我工作中最基本的
Emilio.
艾米利歐
Not everyone will be able to put up with your antics...
可不是每個人都會容許你這樣任性
I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm too excited to be in Japan.
來日本後我一時興奮
I'm reflecting on myself.
我有在反省
Forgive me, Claudia.
原諒我，克勞蒂亞
I'll do my best in the concert. I'll prove that I'm being serious.
我會在演唱會上好好表現 證明自己不是說說而已
I'll give you the best performance, Luciano.
我會做出至今最棒的表演 盧奇亞諾
I'm going to the staff room.
我到工作人員的房間去
You have a stage rehearsal tomorrow.
舞台演練安排在明天
I want to apologize to the staff for my action first.
我想先去和知道這場騷動的 工作人員表達歉意
Yes. You should do that.
也…也對，是該這麼做
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
What did you say to Emilio?
究竟您都對艾米利歐說了些什麼？
Just some common knowledge on how to be an adult.
就是…成年人應具備的常識
It's me.
是在下
You better abandon your hideout.
你還是放棄那個藏身處吧
Those friends of that brat
那個小鬼頭的小鬼頭朋友們
might be knocking on your door soon.
很有可能會找上門
How should I handle that when it happens?
那種情況…該如何應對為宜？
Their phones are all turned off.
那些傢伙的手機都沒開
Are they there?
有在那裡嗎？
They said that they would sleep earlier for the big day tomorrow.
大家說為了明天要早早上床
Professor is soundly asleep.
博士睡得可香了
Don't tell me that...
該不會
Yes. You are right.
應該就是了
That brat is pointing his finger at me.
那小子手指正直直指著我…
Don't tell me that...
難不成？
Yes.
正是
(It's your responsibility!)
（給我負責！)
We really admire you.
我們一直好崇拜你說
Welcome to Japan.
歡迎你來到日本
I'm so touched.
人家好感動呢
Here's a gift for you.
一點小小心意
Please accept it.
請笑納
It's delicious.
很好吃喔
We didn't add anything weird inside.
沒有加奇怪的東西喔
Don't be shy.
請別客氣
Thank you for your kindness.
感謝三位的好意
Listen. We'll follow the plan.
聽好了，要按照計劃行動
When he falls asleep...
趁他昏睡的時候
We'll tie him up.
就把人綁起來
We'll tie him up tightly.
要纏得緊緊的
Then, we'll...
這麼一來我們就…
(The Outstanding Detective Boys!) (Special Edition: Lupin Was Arrested)
（功績卓越！少年偵探團） （號外 逮捕魯邦）
(Inspector Zenigata is shocked. "I admit defeat.")
（錢形警部也大吃一驚「我認輸…」）
Let me give you some tea.
為三位奉茶
They are asleep?
睡著了？
They didn't suspect anything.
沒起半點疑心
Why did I have to hide?
為什麼我還得躲起來不可？
Don't drink anything from a stranger.
外人的食物吃不得啊
You call yourself detectives?
這樣算什麼偵探團
Let's check their personal belongings now.
來檢查身上物品
Are you going to strip a little girl?
你連小女生都要剝光？
Don't make it sound so despicable.
別說得那麼難聽
Fujiko.
不二子
It's a pity. But this is it.
很遺憾，只能到此為止
Thanks to you, the bodyguard has been fired.
託你們的福，我這個保鑣被開除了
There's no need for me to hang out with you anymore.
我也沒必要繼續跟你泡在一起
Bye.
掰啦
You are going to do terrible things to my friends!
你要對我的朋友們做壞事
Let's see how long you can cry.
我看你能哭多久
Don't think that I'll fall for you every time.
別以為我每次都會奉陪
I am an adult.
我可是大人
A thief!
有小偷！
Hey!
你這傢伙
Don't shout that! I'll unconsciously react to it!
直接喊出來害我身體自動反應
Look at this.
你看你看
The information about Luciano is here.
盧奇亞諾先生的情報寄來了
Are you listening to me?
你有沒有在聽？
The Italian Mafia?
義大利黑手黨？
According to the information from the HQ,
總部提供的情資顯示
they are going to make a huge transaction in Japan.
他們打算在日本進行一筆大交易
And this is related to Lupin?
而魯邦和這有關？
I think so.
應該吧
It's rare to hear Inspector Zenigata being so unsure.
難得聽到錢形警部 這麼不確定的語氣
Is something bothering you?
有什麼讓你掛心的地方嗎？
This sounds too petty for him.
太小家子氣了
Does he want the jewel?
他是想要寶石呢？
Or does he want to ruin this transaction?
還是想要毀了這場交易？
This is not his usual modus operandi, right?
不像他的一貫作風是嗎？
He is not the type of target that he'll be interested in.
這可不是那傢伙看得上眼的目標
He has a type?
他…他也是有在挑的嗎？
How's your case?
你那邊有什麼發現嗎？
I've done investigating it.
已經完成調查
But it's pointless.
不過也沒那個必要了
Pointless?
沒有必要？
They are not going to file a report.
據說對方根本沒有報案
Something is not right since the beginning.
打一開始就不對勁
Why will someone take the initiative to call the police
準備進行不法交易的人
when they'll be doing an illegal transaction?
會主動把警察找來嗎？
Someone among them is trying to rebel.
在那群人裡頭…有人想窩裡反
Let's investigate.
來調查看看吧
What are those? Toys?
那些玩具是怎麼回事？
Everything here is not ordinary.
這裡每一件都很不簡單
They are the works of a brilliant man.
全都出自名家之手
He must not be a good man
會給小鬼頭這種東西
to give these things to kids.
一定不是什麼正派人物
Fujiko, what are you doing?
不二子，妳在做什麼？
Fleeing at night?
趁夜逃亡？
What am I doing? I'm going to take them down.
做什麼…去痛宰那群傢伙啊
You are so vicious.
一開口就是腥風血雨
It's too dangerous to go alone.
一個人去太危險了
Did I say I would be going alone?
我有說是一個人嗎？
More friends?
該不會又找了朋友？
It's set.
約好了
Where are your friends from?
哪邊的朋友？
Everywhere.
全部
It'll be the beginning of another world war.
世界大戰再起
Don't worry. I won't ruin your plan.
放心吧，我不會壞了你們的事
Besides, I've told my friends.
而且我也跟朋友說了
Only normal weapons are allowed.
只能使用一般武器
How can we not worry?
這是要人如何放心？
Have you found out who he really is?
難不成妳把底細都模清楚了？
I said that I wouldn't ruin your plan.
都說我不會壞你們的事了
Fujiko!
不二子
Put the kids into the car.
把那幾個孩子搬上車
I'll take them back.
我順便還回去
You are going somewhere else?
妳還要去其它地方？
I can't possibly hide in such a dirty place.
我哪能忍受藏身在 這種髒兮兮的地方
I'm just here to get the weapons.
我只是來拿武器
We'll do this then.
就這麼做吧
We'll steal the thing as you wish.
我們會照你說的把東西搶走
During the live concert?
在演唱會上？
Yes.
對
After relaying this to Zenigata and the police,
把消息告知錢形與警方後
you should stay out of this.
你就別再插手此事
This is as far as your detective work can go.
偵探的工作也只到那裡對吧？
This is my second advice.
這是我第二次忠告
There won't be a third time.
不會有第三次
I said that I'll stop the transaction.
我說了不會讓交易進行
I promised him that.
我向他保證過絕對不會
Relay this to Lupin.
代我轉達給魯邦
Goodnight.
晚安
Fujiko Mine.
峰不二子
How should I deal with these kids?
要怎麼安頓這些孩子？
They might catch a cold if I leave them outside, right?
放在外頭可能會感冒對吧？
So, let's have a deal.
所以我想要來個交易
Will you promise to come with me?
妳願意答應跟我一起走嗎？
(Emilio's Japan Tour's Concert!)
（艾米利歐日本巡迴演唱會！！！)
(Vespania Kingdom's ore is stolen?)
（維斯帕尼亞王國礦石失竊？)
Prince of Music, Emilio Baretti!
歌唱貴公子，艾米利歐·巴瑞帝
Finally, we can hear his singing voice today.
明天終於能聽到他的歌聲了
Okay.
好，OK
Okay. Next, let's interview his fans who have been lining up since last night.
好，接下來去採訪徹夜排隊的歌迷
They chose such a crowded place
竟然選在那麼多人聚集的地方
for their transaction.
進行交易
They are smart.
他們可真會想
When the concert starts,
演唱會開始後
everyone's attention will be concentrated on the stage.
所有人的目光就會緊盯舞台
I heard that Luciano
據說盧奇亞諾
had requested for the stadium to be reconstructed.
有對體育館的改建提出意見
The resting room of the music band
伴奏樂隊的休息室
and the lift under the stage
與舞台下方的升降裝置
will be empty when the concert starts.
開演後完全不會有人
How about hacking into the stadium's CCTV system?
和會場監視器的連線？
I've had it covered.
早已就緒
Do you know how dangerous it was?
你們知道自己做的事有多危險嗎！
If they weren't sleeping pills, you would've died!
萬一不是安眠藥 你們早就不在這個世界了！
I can't believe you.
真是的
How could you leave me behind?
誰叫你們要扔下我偷跑
Professor!
博士！
I'm sorry.
對不起…
I'll think of a way to find Haibara.
我會想辦法把灰原找回來…
Okay.
是…
You are all grounded!
全部禁止外出！
We were right.
跟我們想的一樣
We won't let him stop us.
才不會讓他來妨礙
Haibara has successfully infiltrated the enemy's camp.
灰原成功潛入敵營了吧
Conan will be shocked.
之後一定會讓柯南大吃一驚
We'll depart as soon as we get the green light from Haibara.
一等到灰原聯絡就立刻出發
-Okay!
好!
I can't believe them.
真是
Hello?
喂？
I'm fine.
我很好
It's very comfortable here.
這裡莫名舒適
Yes. I won't tell them about the real location.
嗯，我不會告訴那群孩子正確地點
I'm sorry. They won't listen to...
抱歉了，他們根本不聽勸…
What? Are you talking to that boy?
什麼？對方是那個男孩？
Let me talk to him.
換我講、換我講
Long time no see since our last meeting in the submarine...
好久不見，從潛水艇那時…
He hung up.
他掛了
Why?
為什麼？
The past is too painful for him.
往事不堪回首啊
What? I didn't do anything bad.
討厭，我又沒做什麼壞事
What are you doing?
妳做什麼？
You are so cute.
真可愛
Even your breasts have shrunk?
連胸部也一併縮小了？
Or were they already like that when you were still Sherry?
還是在當雪莉的時候就是這樣？
You know that's impossible.
想也知道不可能吧
I used to have...
我原本還要更有料…
No. I can't fall into her trap.
不行…我不能中計
How about you work with me to complete that drug?
跟我合作完成那個藥物如何？
The APTX of your dream.
妳理想中的APTX…
What are you going to do with it?
完成後要幹嘛？
Of course, I'll first make myself younger.
當然首先就是讓自己重返青春
Eternal youth is every woman's dream.
青春不老是所有女人的夢想
It'll be hot-selling and I'll earn a lot.
可以賣翻了也賺翻了
What a disappointment!
真讓我失望
I didn't create the drug with this in mind,
我當初要製作的 可不是那種夢想藥
You weren't like this in the past, right?
再說以前的妳也不是這樣吧？
You did as you please
隨心所欲
and wrapped all the men around your little finger with your feminine charm.
利用女人天生的武器 將全世界的男人都玩弄於股掌之上
You marched forward with courage until you got what you wanted.
相中的東西不得到手決不罷休 只會勇往直前
A female thief who never looked back.
決不回頭看的女賊
When a woman starts worrying about her youth,
女人一旦只會拘泥於青春
it'll be the end for her.
可就沒戲唱了吧？
Right, Fujiko Mine?
峰不二子小姐？
Yes.
是
It's too soft here.
這邊太小了
More mist in front!
前方煙霧要強一點
Okay!
知道了
This is great.
這樣很不錯
That staff are more united as usual.
工作人員感覺比平常要來得團結
Everyone is affected by Emilio's spirit.
大家都為艾米利歐的幹勁感到吃驚
After this, we'll go back to Europe
日本結束後將返回歐洲
to get some rest.
可以休息一陣子
Are you going to do the transaction in this room?
要在這個房間進行交易嗎？
What is it?
怎麼了？
Are you suddenly interested in it?
突然感興趣了？
Or is it because of the useless sense of justice again?
還是…無謂的正義感？
Mr. Mouri.
毛利先生
I'm sorry
不好意思
for troubling such a busy detective like you.
要麻煩您這位忙碌的名偵探
Don't worry about it.
哪裡
I choose which case to take on based on my personal sense of value.
我都是依照自己的價值觀 在選擇工作
The concert will take place tomorrow.
就是明天了
I'm sure you can't sleep tonight.
今晚應該會睡不著吧
This is now out of my hand.
進行到這裡已經沒有我插手的餘地
I just need to have some drinks and sleep.
我只要小酌幾杯入睡就行了
Thanks to a reliable bodyguard that I have now.
這全多虧有位可靠的保鑣在啊
Just leave this to me, Claudia-san.
就包在我身上，克勞蒂亞小姐
Claudia?
克勞？
I said it wrongly.
說錯了
I will do my best to protect Emilio.
我會好好保護艾米利歐的
Claudia-san.
克勞蒂亞小姐
Ran-san.
小蘭小姐
You are still worried?
還是放不下心？
Yes.
是啊
I won't be able to stop worrying until the seats
直到明天這裡坐滿了觀眾之前
are full of audience.
我都無法放心
The tickets are all sold out.
門票明明都已經完售了
Even now, I'll still dream about
我到現在都還會夢到
an empty stadium.
會場內空無一人
And I'm the only one running around.
只有我一個人在東奔西跑
Running around?
東奔西跑？
I'll sit on every seat
每個位子都跑去坐一下
and pretend that I'm the audience.
假裝自己是觀眾
Because I don't want to let Emilio know.
是因為不想讓艾米利歐發現吧
It's just a dream.
那只是個夢
It used to be a reality.
曾經是現實
Look.
妳看
She's distributing the feedback forms and the advertisements about the next concert on each seat.
他正在將問卷與下一場演唱會廣告 放在座椅上
That used to be my job.
那曾是我的工作
He had performed in a place that could hold less than 30 people.
也在30個人都容納不下的場所表演過
It must be hard, right?
很辛苦吧？
It was.
很辛苦
Because I didn't have the money.
誰叫我沒錢
I felt bad for being so useless.
自己的無能為力教人難受
I couldn't do anything for Emilio.
無法為艾米利歐做任何事的自己
Claudia-san.
克勞蒂亞小姐…
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
Everything is still the same.
一點都沒變
Everything that you asked for is ready.
你要求的品項都已經準備齊全
Including an unused Walther?
包含從未使用過的瓦爾特？
The grip and the spring of the trigger are all custom-made.
槍把和扳機彈簧都是特製的
It's very light.
輕得很呢
You are still as good as usual.
你的功力也是一如往常
Your pay is in that case.
費用就在那個箱子裡
About the pay,
費用…
you should talk to the client inside first.
得請你和裡頭的客人詳談後再說
I see. No wonder I didn't notice anything.
原來是你…難怪無聲無息的
I'm not a monster.
我可不是妖怪
Why are you still in Japan?
你怎麼還在日本？
You already have the sapphire, don't you?
藍寶石不是已經到手了？
You are indeed King. You know everything.
不愧是King，什麼都曉得
Your every move
就算在業界外
is broadcasted all over the world beyond this industry.
魯邦三世一舉一動都是大新聞
Why are you here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
A first-class ticket back to Naples.
飛往拿坡里的頭等艙
Can you take this and go back?
你可以搭這班機回去嗎？
Is this a prank show?
整人節目嗎？
There are no cameras.
沒有攝影機在拍
You should stay out of Luciano's business.
盧奇亞諾的委託，你就收手吧
I know this is against the rule.
我知道這麼做不合規矩
But I have no choice.
這次是情非得已
I don't want to ruin our friendship.
我也不想破壞跟你的關係
Because of a woman?
因為女人？
A boy.
是小鬼頭
Did you screw up?
栽了？
It's not like what you think it is.
應該不是你現在想的那樣
Even if it's true,
就算真是你想的那樣
I won't call it a "screw up".
也不到「栽了」的程度吧？
Of course you won't do this for free.
當然不是做白工
What is this?
這是做什麼？
Yoko Okino's untouched photos.
沖野洋子的未修圖照片
What...
什…
Plus
再加上
Fujiko's naked photos.
不二子的羞羞臉照片
Good.
Good
Everyone, let's start!
各位，開始吧！
I have to use the toilet.
我要去一下廁所
Me, too.
我也去一下
-I'll guard from the side of the stage. -♪ Come closer ♪
我要在舞台側邊把人看好
-Because of this...
因為這樣…
-I'm sitting here alone. -♪ Now, we are here ♪
我一個人坐
♪ That's good enough ♪
這樣就夠了
♪ Take you to Wonderland ♪
帶你去夢幻島
♪ Love you, baby. Sing together ♪
我愛你寶貝一同歡唱
-(Emilio) -♪ Love you, baby. Sing together ♪
艾米利歐！
-Emilio! -♪ Clap your hands ♪
不斷拍手直到破曉
♪ Wherever and whenever we're feeling each other boy ♪
我們隨時隨地都互相感受啊
♪ Dance in a ring then we're together ♪
圍成一圈跳舞讓我們一起
♪ Far in the future ♪
在遙遠的未來
-This is strange. -♪ And it will never change ♪
永不改變
-Not only Lupin,
不只是魯邦 永不改變
-I don't even see Luciano anywhere. -♪ And it will never change ♪
連盧奇亞諾都不見蹤影
-We had last seen Luciano -♪ No matter how far from you, I can feel you near ♪
不論你離多遠我都能感覺到你
-here. ♪ No matter how far from you, I can feel you near ♪
這裡 不論你離多遠我都能感覺到你
-It was 30 minutes ago. -♪ No matter how far from you, I can feel you near ♪
是30分鐘前
-This place is...
這裡是? 不論你離多遠我都能感覺到你
-This door leads to the underground parking lot, -♪ I've been searching for the treasure throughout my life ♪
這扇門可以通往地下室
-but no car has exited the parking lot. -♪ I've been searching for the treasure through my life ♪
但停車場並未有車輛駛出
Look.
你們看 我已尋覓了一輩子
-The underground passage has been lengthened. -♪ But when I began to sing there was no one to listen to me ♪
地下通道被加長了
-What is this?
這是什麼?
-They are asked to be silent about it because it's for the VIPs. -♪ But when I began to sing there was no one to listen to me ♪
以供重要人士為由被要求保密 然而當我開始唱歌卻苦無知音
We had investigated this contractor before.
這家承包商警方曾去搜索過
♪ Now I can see the sunrise in your eyes ♪
現在我能看見你眼中的日出
(Customer Parking Only) ♪ I finally find. This time, I will let you see ♪
顧客專用停車場）
Did you see me?
有看到嗎？
We didn't even see you entering the underground parking lot.
連進入地下道的畫面都沒有
We've been fooled.
我們被耍了
There's a road right beside here.
旁邊就是一般道路
Wait.
先等等
What about the CCTV cameras of the outdoor parking lot?
戶外停車場的監視器呢？
That place...
那個地方…
No. I can barely see your car.
不行，妳的車子也幾乎看不到
If we check the recorded footage,
瀏覽錄下的影像
we may find out where he went.
也許可以知道往哪個方向去
At that time,
那個時間點…
the cars that had passed that place...
經過的車輛有…
That is
這是…
Conan?
柯…柯南？
What?
什麼？
He's not picking up.
沒接
Is he always like this?
那個小男孩平常就是這樣嗎？
He's more excited than usual.
他比平常要來得亢奮…
Am I the only one who feels that way?
只有我有這種感覺嗎？
Where are you going?
要去哪裡？
Use science and technology to track him down.
你們負責善用科學技術
Meanwhile,
而我…
I'll track him down with my intuition.
這時候就要憑直覺行動
Really? Looks like he had found out a long time ago.
是嗎？他果然早就知道了
Emilio trusts you a lot.
艾米利歐很相信妳
He hopes that you won't hold the candle to the devil anymore.
也希望妳不要繼續助紂為虐
-Let me take a look. (Reimbursement Form)
我看看… （請款單）
-Twenty radishes, a box of cabbage. (Accounting Department)
白蘿蔔20根、高麗菜一箱 （會計部）
He even broke the cashier.
天啊…連收銀機都弄壞了
Hello?
喂喂？
What do you need from the foolish Takagi who is suspended and being asked to take care of
請問找因為在魯邦逮捕行動中 出了大糗而被調離第一線
the reimbursement forms because he failed miserably during the operation to arrest Lupin?
一個人負責整理求償請款單的 少根筋又慢半拍的高木有什麼事？
Of course, I'm already done with my letter of repentance.
當然我悔過書也寫好了
What are you talking about?
在說什麼啊？
Is Detective Takagi there?
高木刑事在嗎？
It's you.
原來是你們啊
What is it?
有什麼事？
A new batch of reimbursement forms is here.
新一批請款單送來了
I'm sorry. I'll leave the rest to you!
抱歉，再來就拜託你了
Wait!
等一下
You can't do this.
做人不能這樣吧？
We can only count on Detective Takagi at times like this.
這種時候還是得找高木刑事
Only he will believe us.
只有他會相信我們
I can't believe Ai-chan.
小哀真過份
How could she tell us the fake location?
為什麼要說假的地點
Maybe she had to
也有可能是她受到脅迫
tell us the fake location because she was threatened.
不得已只能說出其它地點
Let's go and save her!
我們快去救她出來吧
Conan said that he'd find a way.
柯南說過他會想辦法
Let's meet up with Detective Takagi first.
先去和高木刑事會合再說
Let's arrest them all!
把他們統統抓起來
Yes!
好！
What is it?
幹嘛？
You are using my laptop.
是妳拿人家的電腦去用耶
Giving fake information to your companions?
給同伴假情報？
I can't put them in danger.
總不能讓他們遇到危險啊
It means that you are good at betrayal?
表示妳很擅長背叛囉？
Just like how you betrayed your previous organization.
就像妳之前背叛原來的組織那樣
But, don't worry about it.
不過，用不著放在心上
Betrayal is a woman's accessory.
背叛就好比是女人的裝飾品
You are going out?
妳要出去？
You can go back now.
妳可以回去了
As a female thief who wraps men around her little finger,
身為把男人玩弄於股掌的女賊
I can't forgive men who tricked me.
我無法原諒欺騙我的男人
Do you want to tag along?
要跟嗎？
It'll be dangerous.
非常危險喔
(Old Haneda Airport Maintenance Facility)
（舊羽田維修機坪）
This is our first time meeting each other.
這是我們第一次會面吧
Nice to meet you, Mr. Luciano.
初次見面，Mr. 盧奇亞諾
I am Alan Smithee.
我是亞倫·史密西
Alan Smithee?
亞倫·史密西？
That is his transaction partner?
就是他的交易對象嗎？
Luciano had only mentioned it once.
盧奇亞諾只提過一次
Did he tell you about the location?
他有說過進行交易的地點嗎？
He had never once revealed it to me.
從以前到現在 盧奇亞諾都從未透露過
I see.
原來如此
You managed to bring it here in the disguise of an equipment.
偽裝成備用器材運抵這座機場
And we didn't pass this through Japan's customs.
而且目前尚未入境日本
Even if they check the equipment now,
就算加以檢查
they won't find anything suspicious about it.
這東西也查不出有何異樣
This is...
這是…
keyboard?
鍵盤？
What you want is
你想要的是…
this one.
這個
You can do whatever you want with it.
要怎麼加工都可以吧
I have the promised good, too.
我也準備了說好的物品
This is the Cherry Sapphire I promised you.
這就是答應要給你的櫻桃藍寶石
Sapphire?
藍寶石？
Why are you giving me that?
給我拿那個做什麼？
Are you joking?
開什麼玩笑
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
I can't believe you.
真是…
You are hiding in such a secluded place.
躲在這種難找的地方
It took me a lot of effort to find you.
害我花費這麼多力氣
What?
什麼？
I once told you that
我曾說過
I'll arrest you the next time I see you.
下次再見面時就會把你捉起來
How arrogant!
口氣可真大
Didn't Papa tell you to stop playing as a detective?
爸爸應該告訴過你 別再玩偵探遊戲吧
I can't believe it.
真是
You betrayed me.
你這傢伙竟然背叛我
You fired me.
你已經開除我了
A special last chance for you.
最後一次優待
I can let you go if you stop now.
立刻收手我還能放你一馬
Scoundrel.
混帳
I won't let you go so easily.
我怎麼可能會眼睜睜地放過你
You've never fired a gun, right?
你沒開過槍吧？
Unfortunately for you,
很不巧
I had plenty of training in Hawaii's shooting range.
我在夏威夷的靶場密集練習過了
How dare you tricked me.
你這傢伙竟然欺騙我
What is that jewel supposed to mean?
那顆寶石是什麼意思？
Looks like we've been set up.
看來我們是被人設計了
Do you know Kein Gejidasu?
你認識一個叫 凱恩·克吉塔斯的男人嗎？
Kein? Who is he?
凱恩？那是誰？
I don't know him.
我不認識那個人
My mistake.
是我的失誤啊
Kein Gejidasu.
凱恩·克吉塔斯啊…
Have you figured it out, Detective Otaku?
猜出來了嗎？偵探迷
Good job at locating this place.
你竟然能找出這個地方
Do you want to know how?
想知道？
Later.
晚點吧
It doesn't matter. Kill them all.
無所謂，全部清除
It's your turn.
你可以好好表現了
Secret skill! Cyclone Return!
祕劍！龍捲逆返！
Goemon, you are making it even more dangerous.
五右衛門，危險程度倍增
This skill has not matured enough yet.
不夠成熟
Don't reflect now.
不要現在反省啦
You are in the way!
擋路了！
I've cut down petty things.
斬了無聊的東西
You are in my way!
我的道行可不同！
Lupin! I'll arrest you!
魯邦！我要逮捕你！
The brake is not working!
剎車失靈了！
-Don't move. -This is the end!
- 不准動 - 到此為止
More reinforcements?
還有援兵？
You are amazing, Jigen. Your shooting skills have improved.
不愧是次元，槍法又進步了喔
It was not me.
不是我
Not me, either.
也並非在下
I've figured as much. Who was it then?
我想也是…那會是誰？
Freeze.
不准動
I got you, Lupin.
逮到你了，魯邦
I'm with the FBI, Jodie Starling.
我是FBI探員，茱蒂·史坦林
You better give up.
勸你乖乖束手就擒
Gunfight at Haneda Airport?
羽田發生槍戰？
Speaking of the old maintenance facility,
說到舊維修機坪
it's an airstrip for private jets, too.
同時也是私人噴射機的停機坪
Are they planning to fly away?
打算直接遠走高飛是嗎？
Area A, B and C are all clear.
A、B、C地區，皆已淨空
He's our opponent. Don't let your guard down.
嗯，畢竟是那種對手，千萬別大意
Why is the FBI here, too?
怎麼連FBI都跑來湊熱鬧？
I contacted them.
是我找來的
I won't barge into such a dangerous area without a plan.
我怎麼可能會毫無計劃 就隻身闖入這種危險地區？
Darn it, I don't have a clear shot.
可惡，無法瞄準
He purposely stands in front of me.
他故意擋在前面
We had once caused a scene in Japan.
我們曾在日本引發不少風波
It's a good deal to hand you, an international fugitive,
把你這個國際通緝犯引渡過去
over to Japan's police and have them owe us a favor.
賣個人情給日本警方也不壞
Jodie, cuff him.
茱蒂，把他銬起來
Got you.
收到
Don't do anything funny.
你可別動歪腦筋
Okay.
是
Wait.
等一下
Don't touch him carelessly.
勸妳別輕易碰他
You don't know what mechanism he has on his body.
天曉得他身上裝了哪些機關
You brat.
這個臭小鬼
Put your hands behind your head and kneel down.
把雙手放在腦後，然後跪下
Okay.
好、好
Let's put him to sleep first.
要先讓他入睡，確實地
What an annoying brat.
真是個討厭的小鬼
You!
這傢伙
Stop!
住手
Go ahead and shoot me.
想對我開槍請隨意
But, even if my brain splatters to the ground,
但…就算腦袋開花了
I'll still pull the trigger.
我都還是會扣下扳機
Please give me the case.
請你把箱子還給我
Take it.
拿去
Don't make a move.
所有人禁止妄動
Can you stay away from me?
可以儘量離我遠一點嗎？
Don't force me to shoot this kid!
別逼我對這孩子開槍
Okay. Calm down, everyone.
好啦，大家都冷靜點
This is a great chance, right? Brat.
這是個大好機會吧？小鬼頭
Alan-san, we agreed on the payment.
亞倫先生，我們說好的錢
Money for the goods.
要一手交錢一手交貨啊
Pilot, can you hear me?
駕駛員，有聽到嗎？
Yes.
是
Start the engine. Get ready to take off.
發動引擎，立刻準備出發
Roger that.
收到
Take the case. The money is inside.
拿起箱子，錢就在裡頭
Bring the car here.
把車子開過來
Yes, sir.
是
I'm Sato. I'll reach there in three minutes.
這裡是佐藤，3分鐘後抵達
Please open the gate.
請先將柵門開啟
What are you doing, Takagi?
你、你在做什麼？高木
This is bad.
慘…慘了
Professor, you can't lose.
博士，你不能輸
They are going to overtake us!
要被超過去了
We have Detective Takagi with us!
我們這邊可是有高木刑事呢
Let's go.
衝啊
No. This...
不，這下子…
This is bad.
可糟了
Please make way.
一般車輛請讓道
Where's your car?
你們的車呢？
We didn't drive a car here
我們是偷偷靠近
because we needed to be stealthy.
哪有可能開車過來？
We've already contacted the helicopter.
我們已經聯絡直升機出動
He'll get away.
會被他給溜了
They are targeting us, right?
我…我們被瞄準了吧？
Put down the gun. They won't shoot.
把槍放下，他們不會開槍
Drive.
開車
Just take off. Ignore the control tower.
直接起飛，不用理會航管
My beloved Alfa Romeo.
我的愛快羅密歐寶貝…
What should we do? Chase after them on foot?
怎麼辦？用跑的追上去？
Even if you ask me...
妳問我我也…
Lupin.
魯邦
Fujiko.
不二子
Who is she?
誰？
Fujiko Mine.
峰不二子
Bust 99, waist 55, hip, 88.
胸圍99，腰圍55，臀圍88
She's one of the international fugitives too.
她也是國際通緝犯之一
Is it over?
都結束了？
No. We are just getting started.
才怪，重頭戲才正要開始
Lupin and FBI.
魯邦與FBI
Both of them ceased fire because of you.
兩邊都是為了你而停火
Brat, who are you?
小子…你是何方神聖？
Why am I the one who's holding the handles?
為什麼由我來控制龍頭？
Do you want to be in charge of the shooting?
不然妳要負責射擊嗎？
Don't worry. It'll be over soon.
放心，一下子就會結束
Wait, Fujiko.
先、先等一下，不二子
The brat is on the plane too.
小鬼頭也在飛機上
Who cares?
誰管他
If you plan to shoot him down too,
如果妳打算連他一同擊落
I'll let go of my hands now.
那我就立刻鬆手讓車子翻掉
Will you share the secret of the drug with me?
那妳願意把 那個藥的祕密告訴我嗎？
Okay.
好啦
I won't use this then.
那就不用這個
You just threw it away.
隨手就扔掉了
Let's use these. Speed up.
改用這個，加快速度
Change the gear!
升檔
Oh my.
哎呀
Sherry. Don't tell me that...
我說雪莉寶貝，該不會…
I used to ride a Harley, too.
我以前也是騎哈雷的
Any problem?
不行嗎？
Keep an eye on that boy.
目光不要離開那個男孩
Okay.
是
Okay. Take off now.
OK，起飛吧
The control tower is babbling away.
塔台囉嗦個沒完
GB27, stop the plane right now!
GB27，立刻停止滑行
A plane is approaching the airstrip.
有飛機準備進入跑道
-JNA301, do not land first! -GB27!
- JNA301，請先不要降落 - GB27、GB27
Are you thinking about...
我想應該不是吧…
I'll stop it even if I have to crash into it.
就算撞上去我也要阻止它
I shouldn't have followed her.
我不該跟來的
V1 (Take-Off Decision Speed).
Vl（決定起飛速度）
Take off.
起飛
Get ready to jump.
準備起跳
Gear up.
收起落架
JNA pilot, can you hear me?
JNA的駕駛員，有聽見嗎？
Don't change your course. We'll change ours.
維持航道不變，我方會迴避
Send an ambulance to the old maintenance facility at once.
立刻派救護車至舊維修機坪
We have a lot of casualties.
現場有不少傷患
Why won't you allow us to go in?
幹嘛不讓我們進去
Looks like we can't do anything about it.
看來還是沒辦法
We have a detective here.
我們車上有刑警耶
Please don't shout.
拜託別這麼大聲…
-Scold them, Takagi. -Thank goodness you are fine, Ai-chan.
- 你去兇他們啦，高木 - 太好了，小哀妳平安無事
-How can I... -Show them your badge!
- 我哪敢啊… - 快亮出你的警徽
Are you saying that Conan is up there?
妳說柯南…在什麼上頭？
So painful. Does he know how to fly a plane?
好痛，會不會開飛機啊
That's right. I almost fell off.
就是說啊，差一點點就掉下去了
What?
什麼？
You tricked all of us, brat.
竟然連我們都一起算計，小鬼頭
Such an elaborate strategy.
費了這麼多功夫布局
What is your plan?
到底有什麼盤算…
What?
你是指？
Stop acting dumb.
別裝了
No one was dead from that crazy gunfight.
在那種亂射下竟然沒死半個人
You deployed the FBI too, right?
那些FBI的配置也是你指示的吧？
You took into account the power balance
要顧及每一刻的火力平衡
and made sure that no shots are fatal.
卻又不會造成致命傷
How troublesome!
有夠麻煩的
If you had let them killed each other,
如果讓他們狗咬狗
the case would be solved.
事情早就搞定了
That was your plan, right?
那就是你的目的吧？
Yes. Everything was going so smoothly.
是啊，原本很順利的說
Do you want me to take care of the ending, too?
結局也由我來安排？
Don't hate me
如果未能達成理想
if your dream doesn't come true.
你也別恨我
Finally, we got it. Captain.
終於到手了，隊長
Yes.
是啊
Now, Gillanba can continue to fight.
這麼一來吉藍巴就能繼續奮戰
You have such a hard skull.
哎呀，你的腦袋可真硬
Idiot!
笨蛋！
Give up. This is his fate.
放棄吧，是那傢伙命該如此
I don't consider this as getting even.
我並不認為這樣算扯平
Okay now. I can smell the ocean.
OK了，有海水的氣味
I wouldn't be surprised if we crashed.
就算墜機也不奇怪
We have to thank the pilot.
得向機長道謝才行
You managed to stabilize the plane in this condition.
在這種狀態下竟然還能穩住飛機
Let me take over now.
換我接手吧
The throttle is okay.
節流閥OK…
It'll be hard to control the tail.
尾翼的控制會很吃力
I got it. Brat.
知道了，小鬼頭
Oil pressure is zero.
油壓為零
This plane has a sub system, right?
這個機型有輔助系統對吧？
I'm surprised.
令人驚訝…
Who are you?
你…到底是何方神聖？
Stop talking.
別再說話了，這小子…
Shinichi Kudo.
工藤新一
A high-school detective.
是個高中生偵探
A high schooler?
高中生嗎…
Your future is limitless.
你的未來…還有…無限…可能
My country has many young men, too.
我的國家也有…眾多…青年…
His country
這傢伙的國家
is being treated as a colony by his neighboring country
正被鄰國視作殖民地蹂躪
with overwhelming military force.
以壓倒性的武力…
What's his real name?
這個人的本名是？
Alan Smithee is just an alias, right?
「亞倫·史密西」不是虛構導演的
It doesn't matter.
有什麼關係
Just think of him as Alan Smithee.
就當他是亞倫·史密西吧
Shoot it down?
下令擊落？
It's a demand from Gillanba's ambassador.
據說是吉藍巴大使的要求
Like I said,
我都說了
that boy is on the plane, too!
那個男孩也在飛機上
Please connect me to Superintendent Matsumoto!
拜託你幫我將電話 轉接給松本管理官
I plan to fly to Hachijo Island.
我準備直接飛去八丈島
How about you go back to Haneda and turn yourself in? The FBI is there too.
折返羽田自首如何？既然FBI也在
Nonsense.
說什麼蠢話
If you shoot me, the plane will crash.
你要是敢拿那個射我就等著墜機
I can handle it myself.
靠我一個人也到得了
It's not that easy.
別想得太簡單了
Even I am piloting this plane with my seat belt on.
連本大爺都乖乖繫上安全帶在操縱
Hurry up and fix the communication panel and radar.
快點把通訊和雷達修好
Okay.
是、是
After I fix them,
等我修好了
are you going to contact Vespania?
你就要回報維斯帕尼亞？
That sounds interesting.
這話說得挺有意思的
When did you find out?
什麼時候發現的？
I figured it out quite early on that the transaction would
猜到被用來交易的是 維斯帕尼亞礦石
involve the Vespanian ore.
其實還蠻早的
And Daisuke Jigen was holding dowsing rods
次元大介在飯店時手上拿著的
in the hotel.
就是探測棒
He planned to use them to locate
他打算用那個來找出
the Vespanian ore, right?
維斯帕尼亞礦石對吧？
He showed it to me in Vespania before.
他在維斯帕尼亞曾秀給我看
He really likes to show off.
幹嘛那麼愛現
You can't be sure that it is the Vespanian ore just with that, right?
你不是單憑那點 就認定是維斯帕尼亞礦石吧？
When they
那個時候
opened the case,
箱子打開的時候
you did a test to confirm it, right?
就曾確認那是不是真的對吧？
Who did it? And how?
你說誰？又是怎麼做的？
Jigen was blasting the microwave towards it.
次元大介用微波照射
And it turned dark although the quantity was small.
雖然只有微量，卻讓燈光整個變暗
Do you want to hear from the start?
要聽我從頭說起？
Sure.
好啊
This might be your last deduction.
這說不定會是你最後的推理
It's not a deduction at all.
根本算不上是推理
It was just a child's play.
這種騙小孩的把戲
The one who kept the Cherry Sapphire in the bank
將櫻桃藍寶石寄放在銀行的
was Eishin Wakagomo.
那個若護茂英心
And for the person who was mentioned during the transaction just now...
以及剛才在交易現場被提到的
Do you know Kein Gejidasu?
你認識一個叫 凱恩·克吉塔斯的男人嗎？
Kein? Who is he?
凱恩？那是誰？
Eishin Wakagomo is Goemon Ishikawa's anagram.
「若護茂英心」是由石川五右衛門
And Kein Gejidasu is Daisuke Jigen's anagram.
「凱恩·克吉塔斯」則是由 次元大介的拼音重新排列組合
You could've done better.
不能再多用點腦袋嗎？
The people who figured Eishin Wakagomo out
識破「若護茂英心」的
were the Detective Boys.
是那個少年偵探團耶
That's why they confidently barged into your secret hideout.
就因為這樣讓他們信心滿滿 直闖祕密基地
What a mean critique.
批評得真不留情
Jigen and Goemon really put a lot of effort into it.
次元和五右衛門想得可認真了
So, it means that
這麼一來
you purposely stole the Cherry Sapphire from Goemon.
就表示你特地去將五右衛門 交由保管的櫻桃藍寶石偷出來
And then,
再加上
Daisuke Jigen who disguised as Kein Gejidasu
化名為凱恩·克吉塔斯的次元大介
proposed a transaction to Alan on one condition,
對亞倫提出的交易條件
the Cherry Sapphire.
也是櫻桃藍寶石
He even recommended
而且還推薦…
Lupin III as the best man for the job.
由魯邦三世出馬行竊
So, it means that your target
也就是說你們打一開始的目標
was never the Cherry Sapphire.
就不是櫻桃藍寶石
Your target was Alan
而是為了接近企圖取得
who was trying to procure the stolen Vespanian ore.
失竊維斯帕尼亞礦石的亞倫
You wanted to find out who he would buy the ore from
並且查出他要向誰購買礦石
and steal it back.
再順道將其奪回
If that Cherry Sapphire is yours,
如果那顆櫻桃藍寶石原本就是你的
I'm sure there'll be a tracker on it.
上頭一定有加裝追蹤器
So, I tracked its radio wave
用這個來偵測電波
to find the location of the transaction.
因此我才能抵達交易地點
By the way, Fujiko Mine didn't work with you
附帶一提 峰不二子是為了要取回礦石
because of the ore, right?
才會和你合作吧？
The news about the stolen ore was even posted online.
礦石失竊的消息還出現在網路上
Idiot.
傻瓜
Who will want to
找回失竊的石頭
locate an ore that has no value?
誰會做這種毫無賺頭的事？
But, you did try to get it back.
但是，你卻企圖要把它找回來
Why?
這又是為什麼呢？
Who knows? Stop with the guessing game.
天曉得，別跟我玩猜謎了
It's because
這是因為
the Vespanian ore was something that Queen Sakura had protected at the cost of her life.
那是已逝莎克拉女王不惜犧牲性命 也要守護的維斯帕尼亞礦石
I'm sure the daughter of Queen Sakura
應該是莎克拉女王之女
has asked you to do this, right?
那個男人婆公主拜託你的吧？
If you could find out earlier that Luciano was the one who stole the ore,
要是能早點查出 搶走礦石的人是盧奇亞諾
you wouldn't have to
你就不用跑來日本
cause a scene in Japan, right?
搞得翻天覆地了吧？
I did it on purpose
我就是忍不住地想放水啊
in order to meet the arrogant detective in Japan.
為了要來日本見某位囂張的名偵探
Whatever.
隨你怎麼說
Okay. You can use it now.
0K，姑且可供使用
Thank you.
謝啦
This is common, right?
不是很常見嗎？
Being silenced with death because you know too much.
知道太多而被滅口…
Image is very important in this world.
這個世上非常注重形象
Lupin III would save someone?
魯邦三世竟然會出手救人…
You should only joke after you've turned on the safety lock of the Walther.
這種笑話還是等你 把瓦爾特的保險打開後再說吧
What a silly joke.
有夠冷的
Eagle one to HQ.
鷹式一號聯絡作戰總部
Please confirm the last code, 1027.
確認最終密碼1027
Last code confirmed.
最終密碼確認
You have the permission to release the missile.
允許發射飛彈
I repeat, you have the permission to release the missile.
再重複一遍，允許發射飛彈
Are you sure the Vespania Kingdom hired you?
是維斯帕尼亞官方雇用你的？
If we can't retrieve the goods...
萬一我們無法將物品取回
If that's the case...
若是那樣…
we have to destroy it before it leaves Japan.
那就在要被運出日本前毀了它
You should've predicted this.
你應該要預想會遇到這種情況啊
I didn't expect you!
你就不在我的預料內啊
You disguised as Kiddo.
你都偽裝成基德了
How could I sit back and do nothing?
我怎麼可能會不採取行動
Don't you have a sense of humor?
你懂不懂幽默啊
Incoming!
來了
Full throttle!
節流閥全開
We have chaff flares.
有干擾絲彈可用
Fire!
發射
This is Gillanba plane!
這裡是吉藍巴機
Calling to Eagle 1 that is attacking us right now!
要聯絡攻擊中的鷹式戰機
The target has fired off chaff flares.
目標發射干擾絲彈
Target not hit.
未命中
This is a demand from Vespania and Gillanba.
這是來自維斯帕尼亞 與吉藍巴共和國兩國的要求
Use the AAM-5 (Air-to-Air Missile).
使用AAM-5（空對空飛彈）
Understood.
了解
The next one shot is crucial.
下一發將會定生死
We can't defend ourselves now.
已經沒有防禦手段了
That's Cherry Sapphire.
那個就是櫻桃藍寶石
I carved it out from a stone.
是我用石頭磨出來的
This...
這個…
Don't tell me that the rock you are talking about...
你說的石頭該不會是
Yes. It's the same one that was in Fujiko's hand.
對，就是之前不二子手上的那顆
That's a Vespanian ore too.
那也是維斯帕尼亞礦石
We have a high-voltage panel in the cargo.
貨艙有高壓配電盤
I got it.
知道了
Not only it's an invisible shield,
不只能當作隱形防護罩
under high voltage,
在特定電壓下
it can disable all electronics.
還能使所有電子儀器失效
If it falls into the hands of a military-based country, the whole world...
要是那種東西落入軍事國家手中 將導致全世界的…
The balance of military power will crumble.
軍事平衡崩毀
Is that the one?
是那個嗎
(Danger High Voltage)
（高壓危險）
What's wrong, brat?
怎麼啦？小鬼頭
Do it now!
快點行動！
This is bad.
糟糕
They are locking on us!
被鎖定了
Ascend and let it fall!
爬升！順勢下降！
That's what you want?
要這麼做是吧
Hold on, brat!
挺住啊，小鬼頭！
Just a little bit more.
還差一點
I only have...
機會…
Now!
就是現在
one chance!
只有一次！
I can't control my jet!
無、無法控制
What's happening?
怎麼回事
Abort mission.
行動取消
Eagle 1, do you hear me?
鷹式一號，有聽到嗎？
There's a civilian on board. Abort mission!
機上有平民，立刻取消行動
Eagle copy.
鷹式收到
But the target is plummeting together with a mysterious light.
但是目標正與神祕光芒一同墜落
A boat?
救生艇？
This is Eagle 1.
這裡是鷹式一號
I've spotted a parachute.
發現降落傘，目視可見
Point 0925. Parachute confirmed.
於0925位置確認降落傘
We are exposed.
全都曝光了
They won't attack us anymore.
他們不會再攻擊了
It'll be the Marines next, right?
接下來輪到海上自衛隊登場對吧？
Together with the FBI.
載著FBI一起
I didn't go that far.
我才沒有做到那種地步
No. I can't trust you.
不，你的話哪能相信
-Go down, you brat. -It's painful. Don't do that.
- 給我下去，臭小子 - 好痛…別這樣
Stop it. My arm is still in pain.
好痛…我的手臂還在痛
-You are like a squid. -I'm in pain!
- 你這個花枝章魚 - 好痛好痛
-Encore! -Emilio!
- 安可… - 艾米利歐…
Did you see it?
妳都有看到嗎？
Yes. You are amazing.
有…非常棒
After this,
以後…
will you continue to watch by my side?
妳也願意一直在我身旁看著嗎？
Go back out there.
回去吧
You belong out there.
你是屬於那裡的
Let's go!
走吧
Okay. Really? Great.
嗯…是嗎？那就好
Inspector. Thank you for letting me stay until the end.
警部，謝謝你讓我待到最後
What are you talking about?
有什麼事嗎？
What?
咦？
In the end, everything has been swallowed by the ocean.
結果最後一切都沉入海底
I hate this kind of ending.
我討厭這種結局
It feels so bad. You are wearing a cunning smile.
感覺很差耶…笑得賊兮兮的
You have the same expression, too.
你還不是一樣的表情
It'll feel weird when you
會覺得心頭癢癢的
do something good for others.
為別人付出什麼
It's like your heart is being pried open by a thief.
就像是心房深處硬被小偷撬開一樣
Idiot.
傻瓜
This submarine...
這、這艘潛水艇是…
Bringing back bad memories?
不愉快的回憶是嗎？
How are you lately, little boy?
最近好嗎？小弟弟
Did something happen between the two of you?
你跟她真的有過什麼嗎？
I hate narrow space.
我討厭狹窄空間
Me, too.
在下亦是
You are indeed tough.
你的命果然夠硬
Haibara? You are here, too?
灰原？妳也在？
What does that mean?
說那是什麼話
If it weren't for me, you would've been burnt to crisp at Haneda Airport.
要不是有我 你早就在羽田燒成一團焦炭了
That's right.
就是說啊
If she didn't say yes to my request, I would have fired a rocket at you.
要不是她答應我的請求 火箭炮早就射出去了
Request?
請求？
What are you talking about?
咦？妳在說什麼？
Are you going to betray me?
慢著…妳打算背叛我？
Betrayal is a woman's accessory.
「背叛就好比是女人的裝飾品」
Right?
不是嗎？
Oh my!
哎喲喂…
♪ Lupin III ♪
魯邦三世
Emilio, come again!
艾米利歐，要再來喔
Thank you, Conan Edogawa.
謝謝你…江戶川柯南
Although there were a lot of twists and turns,
雖然發生許多波折
he still has so many supportive fans.
但還有這麼多支持他的歌迷在啊
He'll be fine.
不會有問題的
What are Lupin and the others doing now?
而魯邦他們現在又在做什麼呢？
I wouldn't know.
天曉得
They must be
反正一定又在
targeting another country's treasure.
打某個國家寶物的歪腦筋
I am a thief.
我是小偷～
He's so naive.
天真哪
Since I'm here in Japan,
老子我都到日本來了
I won't go back empty-handed.
怎麼可能空手而回
What is this? Where's the treasure?
這是什麼？寶物呢？
The best defense is offense, Kaito Kiddo.
「先下手為強，怪盜基德」
I'll arrest you, Lupin!
我要逮捕你，魯邦！
Is this for real?
騙人
He's running away! Chase after him!
他跑了，快追
You won't get away!
你逃不掉的
I didn't steal it!
不是我偷的啦
Believe me, Old Man!
相信我嘛，老爹
As if I'll do that!
我會信你才有鬼
Darn it!
可惡啊…
You better watch out, Kiddo!
基德你給我記住！
If this is the case...
既然這樣…
(Lupin III)
魯邦三世
(Kaito Kiddo)
怪盜基德
(2020 Summer: Lupin III VS Kaito Kiddo)
2020年夏天 魯邦三世 VS 怪盜基德
(I'm the winner!) (Fiercest Battle in History between Thieves!)
贏的人是我！！ 史上最大大盜大決戰！
Just kidding.
純屬玩笑
(The End)
（劇終）